<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="428" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">DECLARATION.</head>
<p>S<smcap>ECTION</smcap> 1. Be it declared, by the people of Texas, in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention assembled, That the territory comprised within the limits of the following named counties shall compose the Congressional Districts of the State of Texas, until otherwise provided by law:</p>
<p>S<smcap>EC</smcap>. 2. The First Congressional District shall be composed of the counties of Anderson, Angelina, Cherokee, Harrison, Hender<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Houston, Jasper, Jefferson, Liberty, Nacogdoches, Newton, Orange, Panola, Polk, Rusk, Sabine, San Augustine, Shelby, Smith, Trinity, Tyler, Hardin, Chambers, Van Zandt and Wood.</p>
<p>S<smcap>EC</smcap>. 3. The Second Congressional District shall consist of the counties of Marion, Upshur, Davis, Bowie, Titus, Red River, Lamar, Hopkins, Kaufman, Fannin, Grayson, Hunt, Collin, Dallas, Tar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant, Cooke, Denton, Montague, Wise, Parker, Palo Pinto, Jack, Clay, Wichita, Archer, Young, Throckmorton, Wilbarger, Harde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, Knox, Haskell, Jones, Shackelford, Stephens, Ellis, Johnson, Callahan, Eastland, Erath, Hood, and Taylor.</p>
<p>S<smcap>EC</smcap>. 4. The Third Congerssional District shall consist of the counties of Galveston, Brazoria, Fort Bend, Harris, Austin, Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery, Walker, Grimes, Brazos, Washington, Burleson, Milam, Robertson, Madison, Leon, Freestone, Limestone, Falls, McLennan, Matagorda, Wharton, Bosque, Hill, and Navarro.</p>
<p>S<smcap>EC</smcap>. 5. The Fourth Congressional District shall consist of the counties of Colorado, Fayette, Lavaca, Jackson, Bastrop, Travis, Williamson, Bell, Hamilton, Comanche, Brown, Coleman, Runnels, Concho, McCulloch San Saba, Lampasas, Burnet, Llano, Mason, Kendall, Edwards, Kerr, Gillespie, Blanco, Bandera, Comal, Hays, Caldwell, Gaudalupe, Bexar, Wilson, Gonzales, De Witt, Karnes, Goliad, Victoria, Calhoun, Refugio, San Patricio, Nueces, Bee, Live Oak, Atascosa, Medina, Uvalde, Dawson, Zavala, Frio, Dimmitt, Lasalle, McMullin, Encinal, Duval, Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Zapata, Webb, Kinney, Presidio, Maverick, Elpaso, and Coryell.</p>
</div1>
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">ELECTION DECLARATION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concerning the Election for Ratification or Rejection of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, and for State, District and County Officers, and Mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of Congress.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1. Be it declared, by the people of Texas in Convention assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bled, That the Constitution adopted by this Convention, be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="429" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Election Declaration.</fw>mitted for ratification or rejection to the voters of this State, reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istered and qualified, as provided by the acts of Congress, known as the reconstruction laws, at an election commencing on the first Monday in July, 1869, and continuing for the number of days specified in the Constitution adopted by this Convention, for the holding of general elections. The vote on said Constitution shall be &#8220;For the Constitution&#8221; and &#8220;Against the Constitution.&#8221; The said election shall be held at the places and under the regulations to be prescribed by the Commanding General of this Military Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, and the returns made to him as directed by law.</p>
<p>2. An election shall be held, at the same time and place as for the ratification or rejection of the Constitution, for Senators and Representatives in the Legislature, and for all State, District and County officers who are to be elected by the people under this Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution.</p>
<p>3. The said election for State, District and County officers, shall be conducted under the same regulations as the election for the ratification or rejection of the Constitution, and by the same per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons. The returns of elections shall be made to the Commanding General, who shall give certificaes of election to the persons chosen for the respective offices. The officers as elected shall commence th discharge of the duties of the office for which they have been chosn, as soon as elected and qualified, in compliance with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the Constitution herewith submitted, and shall hold their respective offices for the term of years prescribed by the Constitution, beginning from the day of their election, and until their successors are elected and qualified.</p>
<p>4. An election for members of the United States Congress shall be held in each Congressional district as established by this Convention, at the same time and place as the election for ratifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or rejection of the Constitution. Said election shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted by the same persons and under the same regulations as be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore mentioned in this declaration. The returns shall be made to the Commanding General, who shall give the persons chosen cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tifificates of election.</p>
<p>5. The members of the Legislature elected under this declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall assemble at the Capitol, in the city of Austin, on the 2d Monday in September, A. D. 1869.</p>
<p>6. The Commanding General of this Military District is re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to enforce this declaration.</p>
<closer>
<signed>ED. J. DAVIS, <lb/>President of Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div1>
<div1 type="article">
<p>Attest:</p>
<closer>
<signed>W<smcap>M</smcap>. V. T<smcap>UNSTALL</smcap>, <lb/>Secretary of Convention.</signed>
</closer>
</div1>
<pb n="430" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Election Declaration.</fw>
<div1 type="article">
<p>DELEGATES. COUNTIES.</p>
<p>Erwin Wilson................... Brazoria County.</p>
<p>James W. Thomas................ Collin and Denton.</p>
<p>P. P. Adams.................... Henderson and Anderson</p>
<p>James Russell Burnett.......... Houston and Trinity.</p>
<p>Armistead T. Monroe............ Houston and Trinity.</p>
<p>W. Frank Carter................ Parker, Tarrant, etc.</p>
<p>William Keigwin................ Leon.</p>
<p>B. W. Gray..................... Red River and Titus.</p>
<p>Cad. T. Duval Harn............. Grimes, Walker and Madison.</p>
<p>J. G. Leib..................... Washington.</p>
<p>W. H. Posey.................... Lavaca. [Fort Bend.</p>
<p>A. P. McCormick................ Brazoria, Matagorda, Wharton,</p>
<p>J. G. Bell..................... Austin.</p>
<p>T. H. Mundine.................. Burleson. [Sabine.</p>
<p>John Morse..................... San Augustine, Shelby, Newton,</p>
<p>Arvin Wright................... Ellis, Tarrant, Parker, Palo Pin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /></p>
<p>A. J. Hamilton................. Travis and Caldwell. [to, etc.</p>
<p>J. Schutze..................... Bastrop and Fayette.</p>
<p>A. P. Kirk..................... Erath, Hood and Johnson.</p>
<p>D. W. Cole..................... Hopkins.</p>
<p>J. R. Scott.................... Hopkins and Lamar.</p>
<p>John Mackey.................... Travis and Caldwell.</p>
<p>Marsh Glenn.................... Anderson and Henderson.</p>
<p>William Phillips............... San Augustine, Shelby, Sabine and Newton.</p>
<p>A. Buffington.................. Grimes, Walker and Madison.</p>
<p>E. C. Rogers................... Fannin and Hunt.</p>
<p>M. L. Armstrong................ Lamar.</p>
<p>Loring P. Harris............... Upshur and Wood.</p>
<p>W. W. Mills.................... El Paso and Presidio.</p>
<p>Thomas Kealy................... Denton.</p>
<p>Ed. Bellinger.................. Gonzales.</p>
<p>Lemuel Dale Evans.............. Titus.</p>
<p>William R. Fayle............... Harris.</p>
<p>A. M. Bryant................... Grayson and others.</p>
<p>William H. Fleming............. Red River.</p>
<p>G. M. L. Sorelle............... Hill, Navarro and Limestone.</p>
<p>Charles J. Stoekbridge......... Washington.</p>
<p>Stephep Curtis................. Brazos.</p>
<p>Benjamin O. Watrous............ Washington.</p>
<p>Mitchell Kendal................ Harrison.</p>
<p>Wiley Johnson.................. Harrison.</p>
<p>J. McWashington................ Montgomery.</p>
<p>Richard E. Talbot.............. Williamson and Burnet.</p>
<p>William J. Phillips............ Wharton and Matagorda.</p>
<p>M. Priest...................... Cherokee and Angelina.</p>
</div1>
</body>
</text>