<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF THE <lb/>TWELFTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>SECOND SESSION-1871</head>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1871</byline>
<pb n="2" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="3" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS, 1871</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the creating of two counties out of the ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritory now embraced within the limits of Refugio County, and to provide for their organization.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that territory comprised within the following lim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />its, to-wit: Beginning at the boundary of the State on the Gulf of Mexico, opposite the center of the channel of Aransas Pass, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the islands of St. Joseph and Mustang; thence, with the line between the counties of San Patricio and Refugio, to the center of Aransas river; thence, down the center of said stream to Copano Bay; thence, with the channel of said bay parallel with the shore, to the east end of the same at the mouth of Copano creek; thence, up said creek to the mouth of Alamita creek; thence, in a direct line to the southeast comer of J. C. Stolberg survey on Esperitu Santo Bay; thence, in a direct line, to Cedar Bayou; thence, through said bayou, to the boundary of the State on the Gulf of Mexico; thence, with said boundary of the State, to the place of beginning, be and the same is hereby created a county, to be called the county of Aransas, and the town of Rockport is hereby declared the county seat of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the remaining portion of the county of Refugio shall constitute and be called Refugio county, and the town of Refugio shall be the county seat of said Refugio county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the present officers of Refugio county shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue to discharge the duties of their respective offices, in the county in which they severally reside, for the term for which they were elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sheriff of Refugio county shall be authorized and required to take charge of all books, papers and records belong<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to Refugio county, and to deliver them to the proper officers of said county, at the county seat thereof.</p>
<pb n="4" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. That all laws and parts of laws contrary to the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 18, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of the Secretary of State, September thirty, one thousand eight hundred and seventy-one, having been presented to the governor of Texas for his approval, and not having been returned by him to the House in which it originated, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has become a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an act entitled an act prescribing the times of holding the District Courts in the Seventh Judicial District of the State, approved March 4, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the above recited act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows: That the district courts of the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral counties in the Seventh Judicial District in the State of Texas be holden at the times hereinafter prescribed as follows: In the county of Titus on the second Mondays in March, July and No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Cass on the third Mondays after the second Mondays in March, July and November, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Marion on the fifth Mondays after the second Mondays in March, July and November, and may continue in session until the business of said court is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>September 22, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="5" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for the mileage and per diem pay of the members, and the per diem pay of the officers and employes of the Twelfth Legislature of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated, for the mileage and per diem pay of members, and the per diem pay of the officers and employes of the Twelfth Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the President thereof, or the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, approved by the Speaker thereof, shall be suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient evidence to the Comptroller, upon which he shall audit the claims and draw his warrants upon the Treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>September 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act to provide the mode of trying titles to land, approved February 5, 1840.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in any action of trespass to try titles to land, brought under the act to which this is a supplement, it shall not be necessary for the plaintiff to deraign title beyond a common source, and proof of a common source may be made by the plaintiff by certified copies of the deeds showing a chain of title to the defendant, emanating from and under such common source; but before any such certified copies shall be read in evidence, they shall be filed in the papers of the suit two days before the trial, and the adverse party served with notice of such filing as in other cases; provided, that such certified<pb n="6" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>copies shall not be evidence of title in the defandant unless offered in evidence by him, and the plaintiff shall not be precluded from making any legal objection to such certified copies or the originals thereof when introduced by the defendant.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of Secretary of State October twenty-three, one thousand, eight hundred and seventy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />one, having been presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval, and not having been returned by him to the House in which it originated within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has become a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the third section of an act entitled An Act to amend an act prescribing the times of holding the District Courts in the several judicial districts in the State, approved August 10, 1870, approved March 4, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the third section of the above recited act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows: That the thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fifth section of the above recited act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows: Section 35. That the district courts of the Thirty-fourth Judicial District shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit: In the county of Bell, on the third Mondays in March, September and December, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks; provided, that when there may m[b]e five Mondays in either of the months of March, September or De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember, then said courts may continue in session five weeks: in the county of Coryell on the third Mondays in January, April and Octo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session two weeks; provided, that when there may be five Mondays in either of the months of January, April or October, then said courts may continue in session three weeks: in<pb n="7" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the county of Hamilton on the first Mondays in February, May and November, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Comanche on the second Mondays in February, May and November, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Erath on the third Mondays in February, May and November, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That, as to the times of holding the courts, this act take effect from the first day of January, 1872, but as to the issue of process returnable to said terms, this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 4, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judicial districts in the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section twenty-five of an act entitled, &#8220;An act pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial districts in the State,&#8221; approved August 10, 1870, be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows: That the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict courts of the Twenty-fourth Judicial District, shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit: In the county of Maver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ick on the first Mondays in November, March and July, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Uvalde on the third Mondays in November, March and July, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion two weeks; in the county of Bandera on the first Mondays in December, April and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Medina on the third Mondays in December, April and August, and many continue in session two weeks; in the county of Atascosa on the first Mondays in January, May and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of. That for judicial purposes, the unorganized counties of Kinney and Dimmit shall be attached to the county of Maverick; the counties of Zavala and Dawson to Uvalde, and the county of Frio to the county of Atascosa.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="8" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prohibit the sale of intoxicating liquors to persons within the scholastic age in the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person dealing in intoxicating liquors, who shall sell or give away to any person or persons coming within the scho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lastic age (as prescribed in the Constitution), without the written consent of the parents or their proper representative, any intoxica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting liquors, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in a sum not less than twenty-five nor more than one hundred dollars for each and every offense.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled An Act to provide for districting the State of Texas into judicial districts, approved July 2, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the twenty-sixth section of &#8220;An act to provide for districting the State of Texas into judicial districts,&#8221; approved July 2, 1870, be amended so as to read as follows: That the Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sixth Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Menard, Mason, Gillespie, Blanco, Comal, Kendall and Kerr, together with the unorganized counties heretofore attached for judicial purposes to those counties respectively.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="9" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act prescribing the times of bolding the district courts in the Twenty-sixth judicial district.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section I. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the district courts of the Twenty-sixth Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict of this state shall be holden at the times herein specified, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: In the county of Comal on the first Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Blanco on the third Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Menard on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Mason on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Gillespie on the sixth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in October, February and June, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Kerr on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Kendall on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of. That for judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial purposes the county of Edwards shall be attached to the county of Kerr, and the county of Kimball to the county of Gillespie.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws, so far as they conflict with the provisions of this act, are hereby repealed; and this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section one of an act entitled An Act to En<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />courage stockraising, and for the protection of stockraisers, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved May 22, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That each organized county of this State, not hereinafter excepted from the operation of this act, shall be created an inspec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="10" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tion district, for the inspection of hides and animals, and an inspec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor of hides and animals shall be elected in each inspection district, at each general election for members of the Legislature, who shall hold his office for the term of two years and until his successor shall have been elected and duly qualified. In case of a vacancy in the office of inspector of hides and animals in any district from any cause, the county court of the county constituting such inspection district shall appoint an inspector of hides and animals for said dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, who shall hold his office until his successor shall have been elected and duly qualified; provided, that all inspectors of hides and animals, authorized by this act, shall be appointed by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor and hold their offices until the next general election for mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>October 14, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of Secretary of State, October twenty-six, one thousand eight hundred and seventy-one, having been presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, and not having been returned by him to the House in which it originated, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has become a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled An Act to adopt and establish a Penal Code for the State of Texas, appropevd August 26th, A. D. 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Title XXI., Chapter II., of an act entitled &#8220;An act to adopt and establish a penal code for the State of Texas,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved August 26, A. D. 1856, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Art. 784. If any person shall threaten to take the life of any human being, or to inflict upon any human being any serious bodily Injury, he shall be punished by confinement in the penitentiary for a period of not less than one year nor more than five years, or by<pb n="11" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fine of not less than five hundred dollars nor more than two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>Art. 785. In order to render a person guilty of the offense pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in this chapter, it is necessary that the threat be seriously made.</p>
<p>Art. 786. It is for the jury to determine, in every case of pros<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecution under this chapter, whether the threat was seriously made, or was merely idle and with no intention of executing the same.</p>
<p>Art. 787. A threat that a person will do any act merely to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tect himself, or to prevent the commission of some unlawful act by another, does not come within the meaning of this chapter.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 18, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section two of an act entitled An Act defining lawful enclosures, and for other purposes, approved March 16, 1840.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of &#8220;An act defining lawful enclos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ures, and for other purposes,&#8221; approved March 16, 1840, be amended so as to read as follows: Section 2. When any trespass shall have been done by any cattle, horse or hogs, on the clear and cultivated ground of any person, it shall be lawful for such person to com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plain thereof to any justice of the. peace for the county where such trespass shall have been done, and such justice is hereby authorized and required to cause two disinterested and impartial freeholders to be summoned, who with such justice shall view and examine on oath whether complainant&#8217;s fence be sufficient or not, and what damages he hath sustained by such trespass, and certify the same under their hands and seals; and if it shall so appear that the said fence be sufficient, then the owner of such cattle, horses or hogs, shall make full satisfaction for the trespass to the party injured, to be recovered before any tribunal having cognizance thereof; and for the second trespass by the same cattle, horses or hogs, the owner or proprietor of the premises, upon which the trespass is committed, may if he deem it necessary for the protection and preservation of his prem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ises, or the crop growing thereon, cause said stock to be penned and turned over to the sheriff or constable; and held responsible to the<pb n="12" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>person damaged for all damages by said stock, heretofore accrued, together with all costs thereon; but if it shall appear that the said fence be deemed sufficient, then the owner of such cattle, horses or hogs, shall be liable to make satisfaction for such damages; and should the owner or proprietor of any clear and cultivated ground, where the fence is insufficient, with gun, dogs or otherwise, maim, wound or kill any cattle, horses or hogs, or cause or procure the same to be done, such person shall be punished as provided in sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion three of the act to which this is an amendment.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 18, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the contingent and printing expenses of the Twelfth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fifteen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any unappropriated funds in the Treasury, to defray the contingent and printing expenses of the Twelfth Legislature; said appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to be in proportion of nine thousand dollars for the use of the House, and six thousand dollars for the use of the Senate; and that the certificates of the Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives, and Secretary of Senate to the correctness of, and the approval of the chairman of the Committees of Contingent and Printing Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of the House of Representatives and Senate to the accounts against the two Houses, shall be sufficient authority for the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to draw his warrants upon the Treasury for the several amounts charged against said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 18, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="13" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act regulating the removal of the disabilities of minors.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any minor in this State over the age of seventeen years, who may desire to have his disabilities as a minor removed, he shall by a bill or petition present to the district court of the county where he may reside the cause or causes existing which make it advisable or advantageous to said minor to have his disabilities removed, which bill or petition shall be sworn to by some person cognizant of the facts set out in his said bill or petition.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said bill or petition shall be docketed on the triad docket of the court and may be heard by the court either in regular order, or at any time during term time; and if it shall appear to the court that the ground or causes set out are sufficient, and that it is advisable or will be advantageous to such minor, in person or property, to have his disabilities, as a minor, removed, the court shall enter up a decree removing the disabilities of said minor, and cause it to be entered of record among the decrees and judgments of court.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That after the removal of such disabilities of minorage, the said minor shall be deemed and held for all legal purposes of full age, and shall be held responsible and shall have all the privi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leges and advantages as if he were of full age, saving only that he shall not vote until he arrives at the age of twenty-one years.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 24, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to facilitate the correcting of surveys and the issuance of patents to locations of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter, when field notes of surveys of land are re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to the General Land Office with applications for patents, it<pb n="14" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be the duty of the Commissioner to cause an examination of the same without unnecessary delay. If upon examination the field notes are found to be incorrect, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office to cause a plain statement of the errors, with a sketch of the map, to be forwarded by mail, or by the party interested, to the surveyor who made the survey, with a requisition to correct the same and return corrected field notes to the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It is hereby made the duty of surveyors, who shall make and deliver incorrect field notes, upon the requisition of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, provided for in section one, or of the party interested, to make corrected field notes and return the same to the General Land Office without delay, without any additional compensation; provided, nevertheless, when there is only an apparent conflict shown by the maps, which does not exist upon the ground, it shall only be required of the surveyor to make an official certificate of the fact and furnish a true sketch of the survey with its connections.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Any surveyor who shall refuse, having once been paid his fees for making and recording a survey, or shall unnecessarily delay to make the correction provided for in this act, shall upon mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion before the district court of his county, by any party interested, be fined in a sum not less than double the amount of fees paid him for making the survey, and not more than four times the amount.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This act shall be in force from and after its passage, and shall be construed to apply to all cases of incorrect field notes now on file in the General Land Office made by surveyors who still hold the office.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 24, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to affirm the titles to certain lands in Peters colony.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the titles to all lands patented in the colony of W. S. Peters and his associates prior to February 4, A. D. 1858, by virtue of certificates issued to colonists by the county courts of counties in said colony, be and the same are hereby affirmed in the patentees and their assigns; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 24, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="15" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the County Court of Marion County to have certain records from other counties transcribed and recorded in said county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Marion County be authorized to employ the services of a competent person to take copies from the records of the counties of Red River, Bowie, Cass, Titus and Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rison of all deeds of conveyances, mortgages, judgments, deeds of trust, and other contracts in writing, of and concerning all lands now lying in said county of Marion formerly belonging to, and now of record in said counties of Red River, Bowie, Cass, Titus and Harrison, and to transcribe the same on the record books of said county of Marion; and said person shall be sworn faithfully to dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge said duties as agent of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the agent so employed by said county faithfully to compare the copies to be taken by him with the original records, and to certify to the correctness of the same in his own handwriting on the books of the said Marion county, on which he shall transcribe the same; thereupon the same shall be received as evidence in all courts in this State, as though the same had been originally recorded in said county of Marion.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the county of Marion to furnish all books, papers and stationery necessary to accomplish the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act; and the clerks of said counties of Red River, Cass, Bowie, Titus and Harrison shall afford to the said agent of Marion county free inspection of the books of their offices, and the use of the same for the purpose of making transcripts and copies provided for in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The County Court of Marion county is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to make a reasonable appropriation to pay the expenses of transcribing the records under this act; and this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 24, 1871</date></dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="16" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amending an act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judicial districts in the State, approved August 10, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section nineteen of &#8220;An act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judicial districts in the State," approved August 10, 1870, be and is hereby amended so as to read as follows: Section 19. That the district courts of the Eighteenth Judicial District shall be holden at the times herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after specified, to-wit: in the county of Brazoria on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in October, the third Mondays in January and the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in May, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Galveston on the last Mondays in November, the third Mondays in February and the first Mondays in June, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 24, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the time of holding courts in the Eleventh Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the district courts of the Eleventh Judicial District shall be begun and holden as follows, viz: In the county of Fannin on the first Mondays in January, May and September, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Hopkins on the first Mondays in February, June and October, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Hunt on the fourth Mondays in February, June and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in Collin county on the second Mondays in March, July and November, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That an act entitled &#8220;An act to amend section twelve<pb n="17" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of an act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judicial districts of the State of Texas,&#8221; approved April 12, 1871, and so much of the same above cited act, approved August 10, 1870, as conflicts with this act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 24, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled An Act to adopt and establish a Penal Code for the State of Texas, approved August 26, A. D. 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Title XXI., Chapter I., of the Penal Code be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 776. A conspiracy is an agreement entered into between two or more persons to commit any one of the offenses hereafter named in this chapter.</p>
<p>Article 777. The offense of conspiracy is complete, although the parties conspiring do not proceed to effect the object for which they have so unlawfully combined.</p>
<p>Article 778. Before any conviction can be had for the offense of conspiracy, it must appear that there was a positive agreement to commit one of the offenses hereafter named in this chapter. It will not be sufficient that such agreement was contemplated by the parties charged.</p>
<p>Article 779. A threat made by two or more persons, acting in concert, will not be sufficient to constitute conspiracy.</p>
<p>Article 780. The agreement, to come within the definition of conspiracy, must be to commit one or more of the following of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fenses, to-wit: murder, robbery, arson, burglary, rape or theft.</p>
<p>Article 781. Conspiracy to commit murder shall be punished by confinement in the penitentiary for a period of not less than two, nor more than ten years. Conspiracy to commit any one of the other offenses named in the preceding article shall be punished by one-half the punishment affixed by law to the commission of the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fense so intended to be committed by the parties charged; provided,<pb n="18" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>that in no case the punishment by confinement in the penitentiary be less than two years.</p>
<p>Article 782. A conspiracy to kill a human being shall be deemed a conspiracy to commit murder.</p>
<p>Article 783. A conspiracy entered into in this State for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of committing any one of the offenses named in article 780, in any other of the States or Territories of the United States, or in any foreign territory, shall be punished in the same manner as if the conspiracy so entered into was to commit the offense in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 26, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to enforce Section XXI., Article I., of the Constitution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the equality of all persons before the law is herein recognized, and shall ever remain inviolate, nor shall any citizen ever be deprived of any right, privilege or immunity, nor be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empted from any burdens or duty on account of race, color or pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious condition.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all public carriers in this State are hereby pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibited, in accordance with the above and foregoing section, from making any distinctions in the carrying of passengers, and all vio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations of the law as herein enacted shall be deemed misdemeanors, and punished on conviction by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars or more than five hundred dollars, or imprisonment for not less than thirty or more than ninety days, or both, within the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cretion of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4 That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="19" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Provide for Appeals from Interlocutory Judgments in the District Courts of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any party to any civil suit that may now be pending, or may hereafter be instituted in any of the district courts of this State, shall have the right of appeal to the Supreme Court of the State from any interlocutory judgment, order or decree that may hereafter be rendered by such district court in such suit.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all appeals, authorized by the first section of this act, shall be regulated by the law regulating appeals from final judgment in the district court, so far as the same may be applicable thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Authorizing and Requiring the Surveyor of Dallas County to Transcribe Certain Records of His Office, and to Make a General Index.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county surveyor of Dallas county be and he is hereby authorized and required to transcribe the records contained in books C., D. and P. of his office into one or more well bound books, which said records so transcribed, and their correctness certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied to by the presiding justice of Dallas county, shall have the same force and effect as the original records from which they shall be transcribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the original books, mentioned in the first section of this act, shall be deposited with the clerk of the district court of Dallas county, who is hereby required to take charge of and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serve the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said surveyor is further authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="20" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>quired to make out a full and complete index to all the records of his office in a well bound book provided for that purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the surveyor, for performing the services required by this act, shall receive such compensation as shall be allowed by the police court of Dallas county, not to exceed twenty cents per hundred words for transcribing.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for transcribing the surveyors&#8217; records.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever the police court of any county in this State shall deem the same necessary, they shall order the surveyor&#8217;s records to be transcribed in good and substantial books, in a plain hand, by the surveyor or special deputies duly sworn to make true copies of the same; for which services they shall be allowed not more than fifteen cents per hundred words, to be paid out of the county treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 6, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for transcribing the land records of San Saba county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The land records of the county of San Saba were stolen and lay exposed in the mountains for several months, and were so much damaged as to render them nearly illegible; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of San Saba county be and it is<pb n="21" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hereby authorized to have the land records of said county tran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed and re-indexed from the original records of said county; provided, that the person transcribing the same shall, before enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing upon his duties, take an oath that he will make such transcribed records true copies of the originals, both in letters and figures.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That certified copies of deeds, mortgages, judgments and all other instruments of writing from the transcribed records, shall be received in evidence in the trial of all causes in the courts of this State, the same as if made from the original records.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the county court of said county is hereby autho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rized to cause to be paid to the person or persons, employed by it to transcribe said land records, such sum of money as said court may deem proper, or as may be agreed upon, out of any fund, either special or general, belonging to said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 6, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Amend the Penal Code for the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Penal Code for the State of Texas be amended as follows&#8212;by inserting after article 363 the following:</p>
<p>Article 363a. If the purpose of the unlawful assembly be to alarm and frighten any person or persons, by appearing in disguise so that the real persons so acting and assembling cannot be readily known, and by using language or gestures calculated to produce in such per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son or persons the fear of bodily harm, all persons engaged therein shall be punished by fine not less than one hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars each; and if such unlawful assembly shall take place at any time of the night, that is between sunset and sun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rise, the fine shall be doubled; and if three or more persons are found together disguised and armed with deadly weapons, the same shall be prima facie evidence of the guilty purpose of such persons as above described; and if any other unlawful assembly mentioned in this chapter consist in whole or in part of persons disguised and armed with deadly weapons, the fine to be assessed upon each per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son so offending shall be double the penalty hereinbefore prescribed.</p>
<pb n="22" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Also, by amending article 488 so that the same shall read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:</p>
<p>Article 488. An assault or battery becomes aggravated when committed under any of the following circumstances:</p>
<p>1. When committed upon an officer in the lawful discharge of the duties of his office, if it was known or declared to the offender that the person assaulted was an officer discharging an official duty</p>
<p>2. When committed in a court of justice, or in any place of re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ligious worship, or in any place where persons are assembled for the purpose of innocent amusement.</p>
<p>3. When the person committing the offense goes into the house of a private family, and is there guilty of an assault and battery.</p>
<p>4. When committed by a person of robust health or strength upon one who is aged or decrepit.</p>
<p>5. When committed by an adult male upon the person of a female or child, or by an adult female upon the person of a child.</p>
<p>6. When the instrument or means used is such as inflicts dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grace upon the person assaulted, as an assault or battery with a whip or cowhide.</p>
<p>7. When a serious bodily injury is inflicted upon the person assaulted.</p>
<p>8. when committed with deadly weapons under circumstances not amounting to an intent to murder or maim.</p>
<p>9. When committed with premeditated design, and by the use of means calculated to inflict great bodily injury.</p>
<p>10. When committed by any person or persons in disguise. Also by amending article 492, so that the same shall read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:</p>
<p>Article 492. If any person shall assault another with intent to commit the offense of maiming, he shall be punished by fine not exceeding one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment in the peniten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiary not less than two nor more than five years; and if such assault be made by a person or persons in disguise the penalty shall be doubled.</p>
<p>Also by amending article 493 so that the same shall read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 493. If any person shall assault another, with intent to murder, he shall be punished by confinement in the penitentiary not less than two nor more than seven years; if the assault be made with a bowie-knife or dagger, or in disguise, the punishment shall be doubled.</p>
<p>Also by amending article 568 so that the same shall read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 568. Homicide is permitted by law when inflicted for the<pb n="23" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>purpose of preventing the offense of murder, rape, robbery, maim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, arson, burglary and theft at night, or when inflicted upon a per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son or persons who are found armed with deadly weapons and in dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guise in the night time on premises not his or their own, whether the homicide be committed by the party about to be injured or by some person in his behalf, when the killing takes place under the following circumstances:</p>
<p>1. It must reasonably appear by the acts or by words, coupled with the acts of the person killed, that it was the purpose and intent of such person to commit one of the offenses above named.</p>
<p>2. The killing must take place while the person killed was in the act of committing the offense, or after some act done by him show<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing evidently an intent to commit such offense.</p>
<p>3. It must take place before the offense committed by the party killed is actually completed, except that, in case of rape, the rav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isher may be killed at any time before he has escaped from the presence of his victim, and except, also, in the cases hereafter enu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />merated.</p>
<p>4. Where the killing takes place to prevent the [?] other person, it shall not be deemed that the murder is complete so long as the offender is still inflicting violence, though the mortal wound may have been given.</p>
<p>5. If homicide takes place in preventing a robbery, it shall be justifiable if done while the robber is in the presence of the person robbed, or is flying with the money or other article taken by him.</p>
<p>6. In case of maiming, the homicide may take place at any time while the offender is mistreating with violence the person in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jured, though he may have completed the offense of maiming.</p>
<p>7. In case of arson, the homicide may be inflicted while the of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fender is in or at the building or other property burnt, or flying from the place before the destruction of the same.</p>
<p>8. In cases of burglary and theft by night, the homicide is justi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fiable at any time while the offender is in the building, or at the place where the theft is committed, or is within reach of gun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shot from such place or building.</p>
<p>9. When the party slain in disguise is engaged in any attempt, by word, gesture or otherwise, to alarm some other person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, and put them in bodily fear.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall be in force from and after the date of its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 6, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="24" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Enable the Comptroller of Public Accounts to Settle with Defaulting Revenue Officers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be and he is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by authorized to make settlement with defaulting revenue officers of the State, or their securities, by compromise or in any other man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner he may deem best for the interest of the State; provided, that no settlement made by the Comptroller under the provisions of this act shall be conclusive, until a full statement of the facts upon which the settlement is based shall have been submitted to the Attorney General of the State, and the settlement proferred [prof<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fered] by the Comptroller have received the approval of the Attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney General.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 6, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Act to Amend An Act Prescribing the Mode of Proceeding in District Courts in Matters of Probate, Approved August 15, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section one hundred and ten of said act be so amended as to read as follows: Section 110. Where a married woman may be appointed executrix, or administratrix, or guardian, she may jointly with her husband, or without her husband, if he be absent from the State, or insane, or refuse to join with her, execute such bond as the law requires, and acknowledge the same before the clerk; and such bond shall bind her separate estate in the same manner as if she were unmarried, but shall not bind her husband as surety unless he sign and be approved as such.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 6, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="25" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Confirm and Make Valid the Acts of the District Court of Collin County, begun and held at the Town of M'Kinney, on the first Monday in July, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, By an act of the Legislature, approved April 12, 1871, the time for holding the district court in and for the county of Collin had been changed, but the knowledge of said law not hav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing been made known to the judicial and other officers of said court, and the session of said court begun and holden on the first Monday in July, 1871, being in contravention of the provisions of said act of April 12, 1871; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the decrees, judgments and proceedings of the said court, had and done at the July term, 1871, be and the same are hereby declared valid to all intents and purposes, the same as if said court had been held in conformity to the then existing law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 6, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Making an Appropriation to Defray the Printing and Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent Expenses of the Twelfth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fifteen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be required, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any funds in the Treasury, to defray the printing and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent expenses of the Twelfth Legislature, in the proportion of ten thousand dollars for the use of the House, and five thousand dollars for the use of the Senate; and the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate and Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives to the correctness of, and the approval of the chairman of the respective committees of the Senate and House, shall be sufficient authority for<pb n="26" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the Comptroller to draw his warrant upon the Treasurer for the several amounts charged against said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 10, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled An Act to provide for the organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation of the State Lunatic Asylum and for the care and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of the insane, approved February 5, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections eight, nine and ten of an act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the organization of the State Lunatic Asylum, and for the care and maintenance of the insane,&#8221; approved February 5, 1858, be amended so that they shall hereafter read as follows: Section 8. If information in writing be given to any presiding justice of a county that any person in his county is an idiot or lunatic, or non compos mentis, and that the welfare of himself or of others requires that he be placed under restraint, and said presiding justice shall believe such information to be true, he shall order such person to be brought before him, and twelve competent jurors of the county to be summoned, who shall be sworn to inquire, and a true verdict render, whether such person is of a sound mind or not, whereupon the matter shall be tried,and if the jury shall return a verdict that the person is not of sound mind, and that he should be placed under restraint, the same shall be recorded, and. the presiding justice shall thereupon order him to be sent to the Lunatic Asylum, unless some friend (to whom the presiding justice in his discretion may deliver such person) will give bond payable to the State, with sufficient security, to be approved by said presiding justice, with the condition to restrain and take proper care of such person until the cause of confinement shall cease, or he is delivered to the sheriff of the county, or other person, to be proceeded with according to law. Up<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />on the trial and inquiry herein provided for, the examination of the insane and the testimony of the witnesses shall be reduced to writing and filed. The proceedings of the presiding justice in relation to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sane persons shall be minuted in the record of his court and certified to the clerk of the district court. Section 9. It shall be the duty of<pb n="27" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the presiding justice on ordering a person to be sent to the asylum to ascertain, first, the number of his family, if he has one, and their ability to maintain themselves; second, the value of his estate, if any, and third, the ability of persons legally liable for his sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port. Section. 10. Before sending a patient to the asylum, the presiding justice shall without delay cause authenticated copies to be made of the proceedings, evidence and decree of the original in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quisition and of the record of all subsequent inquisitions and or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ders, to be forwarded by mail to the Superintendent of the Lunatic Asylum, and in all cases except those of great emergency shall, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore sending said person, ascertain from the Superintendent by ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication in writing, that there is a vacancy and that the officers of the asylum cannot send for him; thereupon the presiding justice shall issue his warrant to the sheriff, or other suitable individual or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dering him to convey said person to the asylum without delay; and when satisfied of the necessity for assistants he shall prescribe in such warrant the number to be allowed, which in no case shall ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed two, and he shall see that the patient is provided with two good and full suits of summer and one of winter clothing. If it shall appear upon such inquisition that any person is legally liable for the support of such insane person, the facts shall all be certified to the clerk of the district court, who shall have authority to order the payment thereof by the person liable, and if the same be adjudged against the property of the patient or his or her guardian, or legal representative, the payment thereof may be as in other cases en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forced by execution; provided, that an appeal may be taken to the district court from the order of the clerk. All persons admitted into the Lunatic Asylum shall be admitted as State patients, except as hereinafter provided.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an Act to provide for the payment of the public debt of the State of Texas, approved May 2, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the action of the Auditorial Board, created by an act of November 9, 1866, so far as the said board proceeded in issuing bonds and certificates of indebtedness upon the ascertained<pb n="28" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and audited debt of the State, be and the same is hereby confirmed, and that the sum of forty thousand two hundred and sixty nine dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lors and fifteen cents is hereby appropriated out of any moneys est on said audited debt up to the first day of January, 1872.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the Governor, at the earli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est day practicable, to to give notice by publication in the official newspaper, published at the city of Austin and in one newspaper in the city of New York, to the effect that the interest due up to the first day or January, 1872, on the bonds and certificates of indebted<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness issued by the Auditorial Board of 1866 will be paid on presen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation at the Treasury of the State, or in the city of New York, or ai both places, as the Governor may direct.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the time within which claims against the State may be presented to the Auditorial Board, as now provided by law, for its action is hereby extended to the first day of January, 1873, and all claims not presented for audit before said date are hereby declared to be forever barred.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Treasury warrants or other evidences of debt pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented for action to the Auditorial Board bearing date after the twenty-eighth day of January, 1861, and which are found by the board to have been correctly issued for indebtedness actually crea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted before said twenty-eighth day of January, 1861, shall not be deemed invalid in consequence of being so dated, but shall be held as valid as other claims dated before said time; provided, that noth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing herein contained shall be so construed as to authorize the allow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of any claim for such unpaid balance or interest-bearing war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants as are excluded by the Constitution.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Auditorial Board shall proceed to act upon all claims presented, and such as are found to be valid and subsist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing shall be audited, and the board shall issue to the holders thereof certificates of indebtedness which may be discharged in the manner provided by the act to which this is supplementary; provided, that the holders of any interest bearing bond or bonds as described in section four of this act may retain possession of the original of such bond or bonds, and the Auditorial Board created by the act to which this is a supplement, shall cause to be endorsed on said bond or bonds the word genuine, which endorsement shall be dated and signed by the President of the board, and shall be sufficient to authorize the payment of the principal and interest of such bonds according to their tenor and effect, and the sum of fifteen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated, to pay the interest and principal of such bonds.</p>
<pb n="29" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. That all interest-bearing claims not presented for the cation of the board on or before the first day of March, 1872, shall not be allowed to bear interest after that date.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the sum of twenty-five hundred dollars, [or] as much thereof, as may be necessary, out of any money in the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury not otherwise set apart, be and the same is hereby appropriated for the purpose of carrying this act into execution and it is directed that notice be given in the weekly official journal for three months, of the time in which claims are to be presented for the action of the board.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That it shall be lawful for the Auditorial Board in act<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing upon the claims against the penitentiary, to allow interest upon them from the time they fell due, at the rate of sis per centum per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to exempt certain persons from serving on juries.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That undertakers, druggists, and each and every active fire<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man belonging to any regularly organized fire company, who are provided with engines or the necessary appliances, doing duty in any incorporated town or city, shall be exempt from serving on juries; provided, that no member of any such company who, when present in any such town or city, shall fail to attend two consecutive monthly meetings of his company or fail to be present with his com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany at two consecutive fires, shall not be considered an active fire<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man unless excused for such non-attendance by a vote of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws or parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 14, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of Sectary of State, November twenty-nine, one thousand eight hundred and seventy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="30" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one, having been presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval, and not having been returned to the House in which it originated within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for and regulate mechanics&#8217;, contractors&#8217;, build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers&#8217;, and other liens in the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person or firm, artizan or mechanic, who may la<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bor, furnish material, machinery, fixtures and tools to erect any house improvement or to repair any building or article or any im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provement whatever shall have a lien on such article, house, build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, fixtures or improvements, and shall also have a lien on the lot or lots, or land necessarily connected therewith, to secure payment for labor done, material and fixtures furnished for construction or repairs. That in order to fix and secure the lien herein provided for, the contractor, mechanic, laborer or artizan furnishing material shall have the Tight at any time within six months after such debt becomes due to file his contract in the office of the district clerk of the county in which such property is situated, and cause the same to be recorded in a book to be kept by the district clerk for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose. If the contract, order or agreement be verbal, a duplicate copy of the bill of particulars shall be made under oath, one to be delivered to the clerk to be filed and recorded as provided for writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten contracts, and the other to be served upon the party owing the debt; both the contract and the account when filed and recorded as above provided shall be accompanied by a description of the lands, lots, houses and improvements against which the lien is claimed; when such contract or account is filed and recorded, it shall be deemed sufficient diligence to fix the same from the date it is filed for record, and secure the lien herein provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the lien hereinbefore provided, if against land in the country, shall extend to and include fifty acres, upon which such labor has been performed, or houses and improvements are situated; if in a city, town or village, it shall extend to or include such lot<pb n="31" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or lots upon which such houses, fixtures or improvements are situa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted, or upon which such labor was performed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The lien herein provided for labor performed, or mate<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rial furnished, shall extend to the land designated, and the person enforcing the same may have the land, lot or lots and improvements sold altogether, or he may have the improvements sold only, and when the improvements are sold separately, the purchaser shall have the right to remove the same within reasonable time from date of purchase; said sale to be upon judgment rendered by some court of competent jurisdiction foreclosing such lien and ordering sale of such property.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. But when material is furnished, labor performed, erec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or repairs made upon a homestead, a lien upon the land, lot and improvements, as provided in section first of this act, shall be granted in favor of the person or firm furnishing material or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forming labor, which lien upon the homestead shall be secured as provided in other cases and enforced as provided in the foregoing sections of this act; provided, that when the homestead is decreed to be sold under the provisions of this act, the court shall order that a writ of possession shall issue in favor of the purchaser, which writ shall be executed by the sheriff of the county wherein such property is situated, upon the application of the purchaser at any time after the expiration of ten days from the day of sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That every boat navigating the waters of this State shall be liable and subject to a lien for all material furnished, labor performed. All actions to enforce any of the provisions of this act shall be brought within two years from the time the cause of action shall have accrued, and justices of the peace shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction to enforce this lien when the amount in controversy does not exceed one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 17, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="32" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to increase the area and enlarge the boundary of Lamar county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the portion of territory situate on the north side of the Sulphur Fork of Red River, and originally constituting the northeast corner of Hopkins county, and which is bounded as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to-wit: Beginning at the southeast corner of Lamar county, running thence south with the original east boundary line of Hop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kins county to a point in the middle of the main stream of the Sul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phur Fork, thence up the main channel of said stream to the junc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the north fork of said Sulphur with the south fork thereof, thence up the main channel of the north fork of the Sulphur to the point where the south boundary line of Lamar county crosses said stream; and thence with said south boundary line of Lamar county to the beginning, be and the same is hereby attached to Lamar county, and the same shall hereafter constitute a part of said Lamar county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from its passage, and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with it be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 17, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to encourage the holding of industrial fairs by exempting certain property from taxation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the property owned and used by any company or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sociation of persons within this State, whose object and purposes is to hold fairs for the exhibitions of the productions of industry, is hereby exempted from all taxation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 22, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<pb n="33" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of Secretary of State December second, one thousand, eight hundred and seventy-one, having been presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, and not having been returned by him to the House in which it originated within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal sections twelve, thirteen, fourteen, fifteen, six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen and seventeen of an Act entitled An Act regulating public printing, approved August 13, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections twelve, thirteen, fourteen, fifteen, sixteen and seventeen of an act entitled &#8220;An act regulating public printing,&#8221; be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 24, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of Secretary of State December five, one thousand eight hundred and seventy-one, having been presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, and not having been returned by him to the House in which it originated within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="34" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled an Act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judicial districts of the State, approved August 10, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section eighteen of the above entitled act be amended so as to hereafter read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That the district courts of [the] Seventeenth Judicial District shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit: In the county of Goliad on the first Mondays in February, June and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Bee on [the] third Mondays in February, June and October, and [may] continue in session one week; in the county of Live Oak on the fourth Mondays in February, June and October, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks; in the county of Karnes on the second Mondays in March, July and November, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion two weeks; in the county of Wilson on the fourth Mondays in March, July and November, and may continue in session one week; in the county of De Witt on the first Mondays in April, August and December, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of. That for judicial purposes the counties of McMullen and La Sal[le] shall be attached to the county of Live Oak, and all process of said courts issued, returnable to the terms thereof next ensuing after this act becomes a law, shall be returnable to the terms herein prescribed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled An Act to provide for districting the State of Texas into Judicial Districts approved July 2. 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section seventeen of the above entitled act be so amended as to hereafter read as follows, to-wit: The Seventeenth</p>
<pb n="35" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Goliad, Bee, Live Oak, Karnes, Wilson and De Witt; and for judicial purposes the unorganized counties of McMullen and La Sal[le] shall be at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tached to the county of Live Oak.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for printing five hundred copies of the rules reported for the Supreme and District Courts, and five hundred copies of the circular letter of the clerk of the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of two hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the printing of five hundred copies of the rules reported for the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme and district courts, and five hundred copies of the circular letter of the Clerk of the Supreme Court, to the end that said rules may be circulated among the members of the legal profession of the State before their final adoption by the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the twenty-second section of an Act to provide for districting the State of Texas into Judicial Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the twenty-second section of &#8220;An act to provide for the districting the State of Texas into Judicial Districts,&#8221; approved July 2, 1870, shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit: The twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />second District shall be composed of the counties of Caldwell, Gon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zales and Guadalupe.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="36" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the twenty-third section of An Act prescribing the times of holding the District Courts in the several judicial districts in the State, approved August 10, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the twenty-third section of &#8220;An act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several judicial districts in the State,&#8221; approved August 10, 1870, shall hereafter read as follows: That the district courts of Twenty-second Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit: In the county of Caldwell on the first Mondays in January, April and September, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Gonzales on the first Mondays in February, May and October, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Guada<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lupe on the first Monday in March, June and November, and may continue in session four weeks; provided, this act shall not take effect as to the times of holding the district courts in Gonzales and Guadalupe counties until after the adjournment of the next ensu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing terms in the said counties of Gonzales and Guadalupe.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All process issued by or from said district courts is hereby made returnable in conformity to the provisions of this act, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, except as hereinbefore provided for the counties of Gonzales and Guadalupe.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to muster into service minute men for the protection of the frontiers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there shall be mustered into the service of the State, twenty-four companies of minute men, for the protection of the frontier from the raids of the Indians and other marauding parties. The term of service to be for twelve months from the day of general muster; each company to consist of one lieutenant, to be elected by the company, two sergeants, two corporals and fifteen<pb n="37" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>men, to be stationed in each of the following counties, to wit: Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tague, Cook, Wise, Jack, Parker, Palo Pinto, Erath, Comanche, Brown, San Saba, Hamilton, Lampasas, Burnet, Llano, Mason, Gil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lespie, Blanco, Kerr, Kendall, Bandera, Medina, Uvalde, Maverick and Webb.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the minute companies, organized by virtue of this act, shall at all times hold themselves in readiness to meet and repel an Indian raid, or depredations on the frontier counties of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the Governor of the State, to see that the minute companies are provided with arms and am<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munition suitable to this service.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the minute companies, shall not be called into the field at any other time than in this act is provided, unless the officer in command shall receive notice that there is, or unless there is a strong probability of a Indian or other marauding raid, or unless he shall receive notice from the officer commanding an adjoining post; that his services are required in the field.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the minute companies shall receive the sum of two dollars per diem, for the time actually taken in the field in guarding the frontier; but the time shall in no case exceed ten days in any one calendar month; and no person shall be entered as of any of the said minute men, unless he is an inhabitant of the county, or the county adjoining.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the officer in command of a minute company shall keep up his communications with the minute companies adjoining, and he shall be allowed to expend not more than thirty dollars per month in this service; but he shall not receive pay, unless he shall present vouchers for the amount, per month, expended in this ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice, therein specifying the party performing service, and the nature thereof; and no money shall be paid from the Treasury of the State unless proper vouchers are had.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the pay of the minute companies organized by virtue of this act shall come out of the balance (after paying off the ranger companies now in service) of the money now in the hands of the Governor, the proceeds of the hypothecation of the bonds issued for the frontier defence by an act, approved August 5, 1870, and should there be a balance remaining of the said moneys after paying off said ranger companies, and the minute men organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized by virtue of this act, for twelve months service, then the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mainder of the moneys if any, shall be paid over by the Governor into the State Treasury, to be applied to the future protection of the frontier.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That every minute man shall provide himself with a good, and sufficient horse, such as the officer in command of compa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="38" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ny shall accept as suitable for the service, and if any minute man&#8217;s horse shall be killed, prematurely disabled, or unavoidably lost in action, the same shall be paid for by the State; the amount to be assessed by the three highest officers in command not interested in the award: that the commanding officer in charge shall make a monthly report to the Governor of the State, of his command, and the nature of the services performed.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That should marauding companies or Indians succeed in seizing any property of the frontier citizens, the same on identifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation, shall be delivered up to the owners free of all charge; and should there be any cost incurred in taking charge thereof, the cost shall be borne by the State. But should there be no owner found for property taken, the same shall be divided amongst the captors, share and share alike.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled An Act to provide for districting the State of Texas into Judicial Districts, approved July 2, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section sixteen of the above entitled act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows, viz:</p>
<p>Sec. 16. The Sixteenth District shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Calhoun, Victoria, Nueces, Refugio, Aransas and San Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricio, and for judicial purposes, the unorganized county of Duval shall be attached to the county of Nueces.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="39" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act entitled An Act prescribing the times of holding the District Courts in the several judicial districts of the State, approved August 10, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the seventeenth section of the above entitled act be so amended as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after to read as follows, viz:</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the district courts of the Sixteenth Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit: In the county of Victoria on the second Mondays in September and January, and third Monday in April, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Calhoun on the third Mondays after the second Mondays in September and January, and third Monday in April, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Refugio on the fifth Mondays after the second Mondays in Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber and January, and third Monday in April, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Aransas on the sixth Mondays after the second Mondays in September and January, and third Monday in April, and may continue in session one week; in the county of San Patricio on the seventh Monday after the second Mondays in September and January, and third Monday in April, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Nueces on the eighth Monday after the second Mondays in September and January, and third Monday in April, and may continue in session three weeks. That for judicial purposes, the county of Duval shall be attached to the county of Nueces. This act shall take effect and be in force from its passage, and all process of said courts, issued returnable to the terms thereof next ensuing after the passage of this act, shall be returnable to the terms herein prescribed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="40" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation of seventeen thousand dollars for the better protection of the public buildings and archives of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That seventeen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to be applied as follows, to-wit: Eleven thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary to complete the artesian well and build two new cisterns in the capitol yard; six thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, to purchase a first class steam fire engine.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the transcription of the surveyor&#8217;s records of Comanche county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Comanche county be and it is hereby authorized to have the surveyor&#8217;s records of said county transcribed; that the person selected by said county court to make such transcription shall be required to take an oath before com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mencing the duty of transcribing such records, that he will make a true copy of the original books. That it shall be the duty of said county court to examine the transcription of said records, and if found correct to make an order of court and have it entered on record, adopting the transcription of said records. That after the adoption of the transcription by the county court it shall have the same force and effect as the original records.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the person selected by the county court shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive such pay for making such transcription as may be allowed by<pb n="41" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said court, not to exceed, however, the amount of fifteen cents for each one hundred words transcribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an Act prescribing the times of holding the courts in the several judicial districts in the State, approved August 18, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the third section of the above recited act be, and the same is hereby so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the district courts of the Third Judicial District shall be holder at the times hereinafter specified, to-wit: In the county of Polk on the first Mondays in October, February and June, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Tyler on the fourth Mondays in October, February and June and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Jasper on the third Mondays in November, March and July, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks; in the county of Newton on the third Mondays in December, April and August, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion three weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="42" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section two hundred and twenty-eight of an Act prescribing the mode of proceeding in district courts in matters of probate, approved August 15, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section two hundred and twenty-eight of the above entitled act shall hereafter read as follows, viz.:</p>
<p>Sec. 228. When the deceased shall have entered into any con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract for the conveyance of real property which was not executed during his lifetime, and shall not have given power by will to carry the same into execution, or such power has been annulled under section one hundred and fifty-seven, the party wishing a specific performance must bring his suit in the district court where ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ministration is pending against the executor or administrator; and the judgment in such suit shall be as conclusive as if the heirs or devisees had been made parties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to encourage the manufacture of cotton and wool in this State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That for the purpose of encouraging the manufacture of cotton and wool in this State, the entire capital stock and property employed and used in the manufacture of cotton and woolen prod<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ucts from the raw material, in this State, shall be exempt from the payment of all taxes thereon, of whatever name and nature, includ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing State, county, town, city and municipal taxes, for the period of five years after the passage of this act. The person or persons en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gaged in the manufacture of cotton or wool, as before recited, shall also be exempt from any occupation tax, by reason of such manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />facture, for the said period of five years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after the first day of January, A. D. 1872, and shall continue in force for the period of five years thereafter.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="43" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize a special term of the district court within and for the county of Houston, Third Judicial District, State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Honorable L. W. Cooper, Judge of the Third Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />conflict with previous claims patent has been withheld or refused by hold a special term of the District Court within and for the county of Houston, commencing on the fourth Monday in August, A. D. 1872, and may continue said special session for five weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 25, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the lifting or floating of valiid land certificates in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever the field notes of a survey have been re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to the General Land Office, and for any cause other than conflict with previous claims patent has been withheld or refused by the Commissioner of the General Land Office it shall be lawful for the rightful claimant of the certificate located on such obstructed survey at any time after six months from the time such survey was filed in the General Land Office, by his written statement deposited with the Commissioner to abandon said survey and surrender all claim thereto by reason of the file entry and survey made by him and to receive from the Commissioner the Certificate on which the same was based; and it shall be the duty of the Commissioner to endorse upon the said certificate that said survey has been aban<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doned and that the same may be located on any vacant and unap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated land, and such certificate so returned to the claimant<pb n="44" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall have the same validity as if the file entry and survey above described, had never been made.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted that this act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 27, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act, received in the office of Secretary of State December sixth, one thousand, eight hundred and seventy-one, having been presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval, and not having been returned by him to the House in which it originated within the time prescribed by the Constitution, has be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come a law without his approval.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act in relation to county bridges.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever any stream is the division line between coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of this State, or when two or more counties are jointly inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ested in bridges, it shall be lawful for the counties so divided or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terested to jointly erect bridges over said dividing stream upon such equitable terms as the county court of each county interested may agree upon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That wherever county bonds have been or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be issued, for the purpose of building bridges, it shall be law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful for the county courts of the county or counties interested to assess and collect tolls on said bridges sufficient to pay the interest on bonds so issued; and, if thought proper, sufficient to pay the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest and create a sinking fund with which the pay the principal at maturity, all of which shall be done under such rules and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations as the county courts of the counties interested may pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act to take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="45" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act permanently establishing the county seat of Menard county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the town of Menardville, in the county of Menard, be and the same is hereby permanently established as the county seat of the said county of Menard.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act suphlementary to an Act supplementary to an Act supple<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentary and amendatory of an Act to regulate railroad com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies, approved February 7, 1853, approved December 19, 1857.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the same proceedings may be had by and before a judge of the district court as are authorized to be had by and before the chief justice of the county, under the provisions of the second section of the act of December 19, 1857, to which this act is sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plementary: and the commissioners that are authorized to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed under the provisions of the second section of said act of December 19, 1857, may, when proceedings are had by and before a district judge be sworn before any officer of the State who is au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to administer oaths.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="46" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of section two of an Act for ceding to the United States jurisdiction of certain lands in this State for pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic purposes, approved December 19, 1849.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section two of &#8220;An act for ceding to the United States jurisdiction of certain lands in this State for public purposes,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved December 19, 1849, be so amended that hereafter it shall read as follows: If the Executive officer or other authorized agent employed by the United States to make such purchase or purchases, and the owner or owners of the land or lands, contemplated to be purchased as aforesaid, cannot contract or agree for the sale and purchase thereof, it shall be lawful for such officer, or other agent, to apply in writing to the judge of the district court of the court in which such land or lands, or the greater portion thereof, may be situated, to estimate the value of such land or lands in the manner hereinafter mentioned, and to order a conveyance of the same to the United States for the purposes aforesaid; whereupon it shall be the duty of said judge, and he is hereby authorized and empowered, af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter reasonable notice given to said owner or owners, their legal rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives or guardians, to hear and finally determine the value of the land or lands in question by a competent jury, under oath, to be summoned by the sheriff or the proper officer of said court, for that purpose, or by a committee of three persons, such as shall be agreed upon and appointed by the parties aforesaid, such committee if agreed on and appointed as aforesaid, to be duly sworn faithfully and impartially to value the land or lands last aforesaid, and the value thereof being thus ascertained to the satisfaction of said judge after survey thereof, duly made under the direction of himself, or by consent of said parties, and after such other proceedings in the premises as he shall deem right and proper he shall order and decree the same to be conveyed in due form to the United States, to be held, owned and possessed by them for the purposes aforesaid and none other; provided, that the amount of such valuation with the reasonable costs of such owner or owners attending such proceedings shall be paid to him, her or them, or into said court for his, her or their use before execution or record of such conveyance, and; provided moreover, that if it shall appear to said judge, upon objection made by such<pb n="47" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>owner or owners, their representatives or guardians, that the quan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tity of any given tract, parcel or extent of land sought to be pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chased as aforesaid is greater than reasonable, he may, in his dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cretion, refer the matter of such objection to the Governor of this State for his determination, and, provided further, that if the Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecutive officer, or other authorized agent employed by the United States to make such purchase as contemplated in this act, shall de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sire to purchase any land or lands owned by private party or parties and not situated within the limits of any county in this State, then, in such case, upon application being made by the said officer or agent of the United States, to the Governor of this State, it shall be the duty of the Governor to designate the district judge have jurisdiction over the organized county nearest to the land or lands whose purchase is thus sought; whereupon, it shall be lawful for the said officer or agent of the United States to institute proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings before the said judge in the county nearest to the said land or lands for the conveyance of the same to the United States for the purposes aforesaid, and it shall be the duty of the said judge, and he is hereby authorized and empowered to proceed in all things necessary to the correct valuation and to the conveyance to the United States, of said land or lands as if the same were situated within the county wherein proceedings had been instituted there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />for, and the said judge shall order and decree the conveyance in due form to the United States, of such land or lands to be held, owned and possessed by the United States for the purposes afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said and none other.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 28, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental to an Act in relation to the location, survey and return of genuine land certificates, passed April 25 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in all cases of the location and survey of lands, by virtue of any genuine land certificate, including Headrights of the first second and third class. Bounty warrants, scrip, and all other<pb n="48" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>valid land certificates, warrants and scrip the certificate by virtue of which the location and survey is made, shall be returned to the General Land Office, with the field notes, within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by law for returning field notes; and the withdrawal of such certificate from the General Land Office, shall render such location and survey null and void; provided, that when a certificate has been located in part, and returned to the General Land Office, the party owning or controlling such certificate, may withdraw the same for the purpose of locating the unlocated balance thereof, and it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice to endorse on every certificate thus withdrawn the amount of land already located, of which field notes have been returned and are on file in the General Land Office, and such withdrawal shall not in any manner impair the validity of the location.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in all locations and surveys of land heretofore made by virtue of any such Certificate, as is specified in the first section of this act, and in which the field notes have been returned to the General Land Office and the Certificate by virtue of which the survey was made is not on file in the General Land Office, nor has been withdrawn for location of unlocated balance as is pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in the first, section of this act, such certificate shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to, and filed in the General Land Office within eight months from the passage of this act, or the location and survey made by virtue thereof, shall be null and void. And in all locations hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore made in which the field notes have not been returned to the General Land Office, they shall be so returned within the time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by law and shall be accompanied by the certificate by virtue of which the survey was made, or such location and survey shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That in all cases when the field notes or surveys of land heretofore made have been from any cause withdrawn from the General Land Office, the same shall be returned to said office within twelve months after the passage of this act, or such survey or sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys shall be null and void. And in all cases when field notes shall hereafter be withdrawn from the General Land Office, the same shall be returned thereto within twelve months from the date of withdrawal, or such survey or surveys shall be null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office immediately after the passage of this act to forward a copy of the same to each and every surveyor in the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act shall take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="49" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of and suaplemental to an Act to give effect to the several provisions of the Constitution concerning taxes, approved April 22, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section thirty of &#8220;An act to give effect to the several provisions of the Constitution concerning taxes,&#8221; be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 30. Where the assessment for all the precincts of a county is made by a deputy of the justices thereof, who is bonded, he shall be allowed and paid a commission of five per cent. on the first five thousand dollars of taxes lawfully assessed by him, and three per cent. on all sums above five thousand dollars, half the above rates to be allowed for assessing other taxes than the direct ad valorem State tax; provided, however, that counties may allow a commission not to exceed that allowed on the direct ad valorem State tax. When any justice of the peace assesses in person or by deputy, who is not also the deputy of the other justices of the county, the above named commission shall be allowed and paid him. Sheriffs or their deputies shall be allowed and paid for distraints under this act what they are allowed and paid for like services in civil suits, and shall also be allowed and paid mileage at the rate of twenty cents per mile for every mile actually and necessarily trav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eled by them in going to and returning from the capital in order to settle their accounts and pay into the Treasury the taxes collected by them: they shall be allowed and paid commission for collecting all State, occupation and direct ad valorem taxes, five per cent. on the first five thousand dollars, and three per cent. on all sums above five thousand dollars, and shall be allowed and paid one-half of the above rates for collecting all other taxes. The commissions above described, to which justices of the peace are entitled for assessing, together with the commissions of sheriffs for collecting the taxes, shall be paid out of the general revenue; provided, nevertheless, that when the total compensation for assessing or for collecting in any county shall exceed the sum of four thousand dollars, the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess shall be paid into the State Treasury, and shall be applied in like manner with the direct ad valorem tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="50" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the printing and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent expenses of the Twelfth Legislature of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of twenty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fray the printing and contingent expense of the Twelfth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture of the State of Texas, said appropriation to be in proportion of thirteen thousand dollars for the House of Representatives and seven thousand for the Senate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to and amendatory of an Act entitled An Act to organize and maintain a system of public free schools in the State of Texas, approved April 24, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the above recited act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows, viz.: Clause 1. The Board of Educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall, upon the passage of this act proceed to apportion anew the territory of this State into convenient educational districts, not to exceed twelve in number; provided, that nothing in this clause dhall be construed as to prohibit said board hereafter from consoli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tating or otherwise changing or altering the boundaries of said dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sricts for educational purposes. Clause 2. And as soon as the educational districts contemplated in the foregoing clause shall be created, it shall be the duty of Superintendent of Public In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction to retire or relieve from duty each supervisor of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion heretofore appointed and commissioned as such; and the said<pb n="51" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Superintendent is hereby authorized to appoint, with the approval of the Governor, for each newly created district, one supervisor of education, who shall hold his office for the term of four years from the date of his commission, unless sooner removed by said Superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent, for cause, on the approval of the Governor; and the super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visor may act as examiner of teachers. Clause 3. And each super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visor so appointed shall receive for his services, out of any moneys belonging to the available school fund not otherwise appropriated, first, a salary of eighteen hundred dollars per annum; second, all expenses for postage; and third, all traveling expenses necessarily incurred while employed in the actual discharge of the duties of his office; provided, that the amount of the above mentioned ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses shall not exceed the sum of two hundred dollars, on voucher to be approved by the Superintendent of Public Instruction, during any one scholastic year. Clause 4. And the supervisors herein pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for shall be empowered to lay off and subdivide the counties in the territory under their jurisdiction into convenient school dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts; and they shall also appoint, on the approval of the Superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent of Public Instruction, five directors for each school district; but the authority of the said supervisors in the management, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol and oversight of their respective districts shall be subject to the control, direction and revision of the said Superintendent; and it shall be the further duty of the said supervisors to enforce in their respective districts all rules and regulations adopted by the Board of Education for the government of the public free schools in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the unexpended balance of the deficiency appropriation for the scholastic year ending on the thirty-first day of August, 1871, be and the same is hereby added to and made a part of the appropriation for the scholastic year end<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing thirty-first day of August, 1871,* and to be apportioned as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by section one of the above cited act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Superintendent of Public Instruction, with the approval of the Governor, shall make requisition from time to time for such sums of money as may be necessary to pay the teachers and employes of the Bureau of Education, out of any funds in the Treasury appropriated for that purpose, which shall be sufficient authority for the Comptroller to issue a warrant therefor,<pb n="52" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and the Superintendent of Public Instruction shall, on disbursing each requisition, file his vouchers with the Comptroller of Public Accounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section one and to repeal section six of an Act to authorize county courts to levy a road tax and to improve roads and bridges, passed August 4, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section one of &#8220;An act to authorize county courts to levy a road tax and to improve roads and bridges,&#8221; passed August 4, 1870, be so amended that hereafter it shall read as follows, viz.:</p>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county courts of the several counties of this State, are hereby authorized to appropriate the annual taxes collected in their respective counties for public roads and bridges, to the building of bridges and the improvement of the first class public roads in their respective counties; said roads to be classed by said county courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section six of the act before recited, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage; provided, that it shall be lawful for the proper officers to collect the tax provided for in the section hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed, in all cases where the same had been assessed prior to the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="53" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal sections one, two and three of an Act providing for the payment of the outstanding indebtedness of the several counties, passed July 21, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections one, two and three of &#8220;An act providing for the payment of the outstanding indebtedness of the several coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties,&#8221; passed July 21, 1870, be and they are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage; provided, that it shall be lawful for the proper officers to collect and to expend, for the purpose expressed in the act before recited, all taxes assessed in accordance with the said act prior to the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the practice in the Supreme Court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any party to the record, in any cause now pending in, or hereafter taken to the Supreme Court, by appeal or writ of error, shall have died heretofore, or shall hereafter die, after the appeal bond has been filed and approved, or after the writ of error has been served, and before such cause has been decided by the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court, such cause shall not abate by such death, but the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court shall proceed to adjudicate such cause, and render judgment therein as if all the parties thereto were still living, and such judgment shall have the same force and effect, as if rendered in the lifetime of all the parties thereto; provided, however, that this act shall not apply to any suit or action in which the cause of action does not survive in favor or against the legal representatives of a deceased person.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="54" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to the Act entitled an Act to adopt and establish a penal code for the State of Texas, approved, twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eighth of August, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That every person, or a member of a firm, or corporation, subject to the payment of an occupation tax, who shall neglect or fail, after having been duly notified by any officer charged with the collection of any such occupation tax, to comply with any one of the several provisions of an act, entitled an act to give effect to the several pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the Constitution concerning taxes, approved April 22, 1871, concerning occupation tax, shall be deemed guilty of a mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanor, and shall on conviction, on indictment, or information, be punished by a fine of not less than five, nor more than one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Any officer who is charged by law with the assessment or collection of taxes, who shall fail to comply with any one of the requirements of the law concerning taxes, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall upon conviction on information, be pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished by fine, not less than five nor more than one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Making Appropriations for the Support of the State Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment for Deficiencies for the Fiscal Year Beginning Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber 1, 1871, and ending August 31, 1872.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same are hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the support of the State government and for deficiencies incurred in the support of the State government for the fiscal year beginning September 1, 1871, and ending August 31, 1872:</p>
<pb n="55" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Executive Department.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Deficiences.</head>
<p>For postage, stationery and contingent expenses, one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.$1,000 00</p>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">State Department.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Deficiencies.</head>
<p>For printing laws and journals of Twelfth Legislature, three thousand six hundred dollars.$3,600 00</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Treasury report, two hundred and forty dollars. 240 00</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Adjutant General&#8217;s report, four hundred and sixty-three dollars and thirty-five cents.. 463 35</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Secretary of State&#8217;s report, two hundred and forty-six dollars and sixty-five cents.... 246 65</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Commissioner of General Land Office&#8217;s report, ninety-nine dollars and ninety-five cents 99 95</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Deaf and Dumb Asylum Report, eighty-three dollars and thirty cents. 83 30</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Superintendent Immigration&#8217;s report, thirty-three dollars and thirty cents. 33 30</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Blind Asylum report, twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />six dollars and sixty-five cents. 26 65</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Lunatic Asylum report, two hundred and ten dollars. 210 00</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Penitentiary report, three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty-three dollars and thirty-five cents.... 343 35</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies Attorney General&#8217;s report, nine hundred and forty-six dollars and fifty cents. 946 50</p>
<p>For printing 200 copies Superintendent Lunatic Asylum report, one hundred and fixty-six dollars and fifty cents, 156 50</p>
<p>For printing 1,000 copies additional Trustees Blind Asy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lum report, eighty dollars. 80 00</p>
<p>For printing laws and journals Twelfth Legislature, ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed session, eight thousand dollars. 8,000 00</p>
<p>For advertising tax law, four thousand dollars, four thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars. 4,000 00</p>
<p>For stationery, postage and contingent expenses, five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars. 500 00</p>
</div4>
<pb n="56" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">School Department.</head>
<p>For traveling expenses and mileage, one thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars..$1,000 00</p>
<p>For furnishing office of Superintendent Public Instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, twelve hundred dollars. 1,200 00</p>
<p>For postage, telegraphing, wood and contingent expenses, two thousand dollars. 2,000 00</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act further prescribing the time of holding the terms of the district courts in the eighth judicial district.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the term of the district court shall be holden in the county of Delta on the fourth Mondays of December, April and August of each year, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith are hereby repealed, and this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the surveyor of Johnson county to transcribe certain books in his office.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county surveyor of Johnson county be and is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by authorized to transcribe record book C., and file book A., into suitable books for that purpose, and that he be allowed such com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation as is allowed for similar services by law out of any money in the county treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="57" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal section seven (7) of an Act to give effect to the several provisions of the constitution concerning taxes, approved April 22, 1871, as amended by an Act amendatory of and sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plemental to an Act to give effect to the several provisions of the Constitution concerning taxes, approved April 25, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section (7) of &#8220;An Act to give effect to the several provisions of the Constitution concerning taxes,&#8221; approved April 22, 1871, as amended by &#8220;An act amendatory of and supplemental to &#8216;an act to give effect to the several provisions of the Constitution concerning taxes,' &#8221; approved April 25, 1871, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act validating certain land certificates.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all land certificates issued by the Commissioner of the General Land Office by authority of the act of February 11, 1858, and acts amendatory thereof of February 1, 1860, and January 1, 1862, and in conformity therewith, are hereby validated so far as said certificates may be invalid by reason of having been issued subsequent to February 1, 1861.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="58" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section nineteen of an Act to regulate ferries, approved January 23, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section nineteen of &#8220;An act to regulate ferries,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved January 23, 1850, be and it is hereby amended so that here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after it shall read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 19. If any water course, navigable stream, lake or bay shall form a portion of the boundary of any county, so that one bank shall be in one county and the other in a different county, at the place where it is proposed to establish a ferry, or where a ferry has been established, the application for a license shall be made to the county court of the county wherein the applicant resides or has his ferry house, and upon the granting of such license by the said court, the person or persons so licensed shall have the right to own and operate a ferry upon the same terms and conditions and with the same rights and privileges as are provided by this act for the own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers or keepers of ferries operated exclusively in one county, and no county tax shall be assessed and collected upon a ferry by any other county court than the one granting the license therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section thirty-four of an Act to organize the courts of justices of the peace and county courts, and to define their jurisdiction and duties, approved August 13, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section thirty-four of &#8220;An act to organize the courts of justices of the peace and county courts, and to define their juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction and duties,&#8221; approved August 13, 1870, shall be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<pb n="59" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 34. A regular term of the county court shall commence and be held at the court house of each county in the State on the last Mondays in January, March, May, July, September and No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember in every year, for the transaction of all business growing out of or connected with the powers and jurisdiction of said court; such terms shall be held by the presiding justice, with the assistance of any two or more of the other justices, and may continue for three or more days; and special terms of said court may be held in like manner and for like purposes, as provided for in this section, at such other times as the presiding justice may appoint; provided, however, that no county tax shall be levied, unless at some one of the regular terms of said court. The justices of the peace, when sitting at any regular term of the county court, shall receive a compensation of four dollars a day; provided, however, that they shall not be entitled to compensation for more than four days at any one regular session, and no compensation shall be allowed when holding a special session. Their compensation shall be drawn from the county treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and all laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the division of the records in Refugio and Aransas counties and their transfer to their proper counties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the district clerk of Aransas county, be and he is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by authorized and required to immediately make a division of the cases on the court docket in his office, and transfer them to the proper county in which the defendants reside; provided, the same be civil cases, but in all criminal actions, the cases shall be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred to the county in which the offenses were committed, and the jurisdiction of the court of the county shall attach in accordance with such division and transfer.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all the books and records properly belonging to Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fugio county, shall be immediately turned over and delivered by the officers of Aransas to the proper officer or officers of said county of<pb n="60" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Refugio, when elected or appointed, on demand; whose duty it shall be to take charge of the same and remove them to the county seat of Refugio county and keep the same in the proper offices to be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by the county court of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process issued shall be returnable to the court of the county whose jurisdiction attaches, and shall have full force and effect therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the district clerk having in charge the books and records of Refugio county, shall immediately transcribe from them in the proper manner, such records as are absolutely essential to the successful transaction of the business of the courts of Aransas county, for which he shall be paid a reasonable compensation by the county of Aransas.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That it shall be the duty of the county court of said county of Aransas to examine all copies of records made under the provisions of this act and if found to be correct they shall certify to the same, and such certified copies shall have all the force and effect of the originals in all the tribunals of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Amendatory of Section 5 of An Act to Give Effect to the Several Provisions of the Constitution Concerning Taxes, Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved April 22, 1871.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section five of &#8220;An act to give effect to the several pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the Constitution concerning taxes,&#8221; approved April 22, 1871, be so amended that hereafter it shall read as follows: An annual direct ad valorem tax of one-eighth of one per centum shall be levied, on the value of all property subject to taxation thereby for public roads and bridges, to be applied by the county courts, subject to such regulations as the Legislature may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 2 That this act shall take effect and be in force, from and after its passage; provided, that it shall be lawful for the proper officers to collect the one-fourth of one per centum provided for in this section to which this act is an amendment, in all cases where the same had been assessed, prior to the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="61" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Repeal An Act to Authorize the Police Courts of Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties to Levy and Collect a Special Tax for the Repair and Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pletion of Puclic Buildings, Passed August 5, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That &#8220;An act to authorize the police courts of counties to levy and collect a special tax for the repair and completion of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic buildings,&#8221; passed August 5, 1870, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage; provided, that it shall be lawful for the proper officers to collect and expend for the purposes expressed in the act hereby repealed all taxes assessed in accordance with the provisions of the said act prior to the passage of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Amend An Act entitled An Act to Regulate the Times of Holding the Courts in the Eleventh Judicial District, Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved October, 24, A. D. 1871</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section one of the above recited act be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 1. That the District Courts of the Eleventh Judicial District, shall be begun and holden as follows: In the county of Fannin, on the first Mondays in January, May and September, and may continue in session four weeks: in the county of Hop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kins on the first Mondays in February, June and October, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Hunt on the fourth Mondays in February, June and October, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Collin, on the third Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March, July and November, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="62" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Further Regulating Juries.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter all the qualified voters of each county shall be qualified jurors of such county; provided, that every person hereafter convicted of bribery, perjury, forgery, or other felony or high crime, shall be excluded from serving on juries, and provided further, that all persons shall be exempt from jury service, as is now provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Each county court in this State shall, immediately after the passage of this act, and at least twenty days before the first day of the next ensuing term of the district court to be held for their county, prepare a list of all the qualified voters of their respective counties, which list shall be copied in a well bound book by the clerk of the district court, and said county court shall place tickets, with the names of the voters thereon, separately in a suitable box, to be designated &#8220;jury box number one;&#8221; and shall draw there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />from the names of twenty persons to serve as grand jurors for the next ensuing term of the district court, and twenty-four persons to serve as pettit jurors for each week provided by law for the holding of the district court for their county, and, as they are drawn, the tickets on which their names are written shall be placed in a suit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able box, to be designated &#8220;jury box number two.;&#8221; and said jury boxes and jury books shall, after drawing be turned over to the clerks of the district court respectively, who shall securely keep the same in their respective offices, and who shall be held responsible for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. After the first drawing of jurors, as provided in the foregoing section, grand and petit jurors for service in the district courts shall be drawn in the following man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, to-wit: Under the direction of the district judge, in open court, on one day of the last week of the court, the time to be previously designated by the judge; and not less than fifteen nor more than twenty persons shall be drawn as grand jurors, and twenty-four persons for petit jurors, for each week the district court may be in session, and the names of the persons so chosen, and all the proceedings relating to the drawing of the same, shall be entered by the clerk on the minutes of the court, and whenever the tickets in box number one shall be exhausted, then the contents of box number two shall be placed in box number one, so that the jury service shall be as nearly as possible equalized.<pb n="63" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>And in case the district judge shall fail for any cause to hold court, then the county court of each county and the district clerk shall, within thirty days after said failure, draw such jurors in open court, at the court house, after giving five days&#8217; public notice of such drawing posted before the court house door, and the names of the jurors drawn, and all the proceedings had in relation thereto before said court, shall be duly entered on the minutes of the district court and signed by the justices and clerk.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Immediately after any registration of voters in any county of this State, the district judge shall cause the names of all newly registered voters to be placed on separate tickets, which shall be placed in jury box number one, and at any drawing of jurors, if the name of any person shall be drawn who, within the knowledge of the court, is unable by reason of his absence from the county to attend the court, or who has become disqualified to serve as juror since his name was placed in the jury box, or who is privileged by law from serving, the court shall cause the ticket upon which the name of such person is written to be replaced in jury box number one, and another shall be drawn in its stead.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. It shall be the duty of the clerk of the district court, immediately or within five days after the drawing of jurors, as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated in sections two and three of this act, has been made, to issue a &#8220;venire facias&#8221; in due form, as is now required by law, and the sheriff or other officer shall execute the &#8220;venire&#8221; for jurors, as is now provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. In civil suits in the district court, each party shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be entitled to challenge six jurors without showing any cause therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. All other proceedings whatever in relation to juries, their organization, service and compensation, shall remain as is now provided by law; and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="64" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Punish Certain Offenses Committed on Sunday.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person or persons who shall hereafter labor, or compel, force or oblige his or her employes, workmen or apprentices to labor on the Lord&#8217;s day, shall be deemed guilty of a misde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />meanor, and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in a sum of not less than ten, nor more than fifty dollars; provided, that household duties, works of necessity and charity shall not be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibited by this act; and provided further, that this act shall not apply to any work done on plantations and farms that may be necessary to prevent the loss of any crop or crops.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That nothing in the foregoing section shall be so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued as to apply to the running of steamboats or other water crafts, rail cars, wagon trains, common carriers, or to the delivery of goods by them or the receiving or storing of said goods by the parties or their agents to whom said goods are delivered, or to stages carrying the United States mail or passengers, foundries, sugar mills, or to stock keepers or herders who have a herd of stock actually gathered and under herd, or to persons traveling on the public highway, or ferrymen or keepers of toll bridges, keepers of hotels, boarding houses, restaurants and their servants, keepers of livery stables and their servants; provided, that nothing herein be so construed as to apply to any person who conscientiously believes that the seventh or any other day of the week ought to be observed as the Sabbath, and who actually refrains from business and labor on that day for secular reasons.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That any person or persons who shall run or be engaged in running any horse races or who shall permit or allow the use of any nine or ten pin alley, or who shall be engaged in match shoot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or any species of gaming for money or other consideration, within the limits of any city or town on Sunday, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be fined not less than twenty nor more than fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That any merchant, grocer or dealer in wares or mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandise or trader in any lawful business whatsoever, who shall sell or barter on Sunday between the hours of 9 o&#8217;clock A. M. and 4 o&#8217;clock P. M. within the limits of any city or town, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in a sum of not less than twenty nor more than fifty dollars; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="65" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>vided, that nothing contained in this act shall be construed to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibit the sale of drugs and medicines on Sunday.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That an act entitled &#8220;An act to punish certain offenses committed on Sunday,&#8221; approved December 16, 1863, and all other laws and parts of laws contrary to or conflicting with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Authorizing a Loan to Meet Deficiencies in the Revenue of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of the State is hereby authorized to have engraved the bonds of the State of Texas, to the amount of two millions of dollars, as follows: First&#8212;One million of dollars in bonds of the denomination of one thousand dollars each. Second&#8212; Five hundred thousand dollars in bonds of the denomination of five hundred dollars each. Third&#8212;Five hundred thousand dollars in bonds of the denomination of one hundred dollars each.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said bonds shall be payable twenty (20) years from the date thereof, and shall bear interest at the rate of seven per centum per annum, payable semi-annually, viz: on the first day of January and the first day of July of each year, said bonds to have coupons attached for each installment of interest which may become due. The principal and interest of said bonds shall be pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able in gold at the Treasury of the State of Texas, or at the city of New York, through such agent or agents as the Governor may select to pay the sarnie.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said bonds shall be signed by the Governor and the Treasurer of the State of Texas, and shall be countersigned and registered by the Comptroller with the seal of the State of Texas affixed thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Governor shall appoint an agent in the city of New York, who shall sell the bonds provided for in this act, at such times and in such quantities as the Governor may direct, and the Governor shall cause the proceeds from such sales to be placed in the Treasury of tho State. The Governor is hereby authorized to<pb n="66" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>allow the said agent such percentage upon the bonds sold by him as he may find necessary to secure the sale of said bonds to the best advantage for the State; provided, that within ten days after the receipt of information of the sale of any of the bonds provided for in this act, in case the Legislature shall be in session, and otherwise within ten days after the re-assembling of the Legislature, it shall be the duty of the Governor to inform the Legislature by message of the value of the bonds sold, the amount of the moneys received therefor by the State, the name of the agent through whom the bonds were sold, and the per centage allowed such agent upon the bonds so sold.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the proceeds from the sale of said bonds shall be applied exclusively to the payment of claims upon the State, arising from appropriations made by law, to the payment of interest due and to become due upon the public debt of the State, and to consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tute the sinking fund required by the Constitution and laws of the State, for the redemption of the principal of the public debt of the State, in any case where no other adequate provision shall have been made therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Treasurer of the State shall be and he is hereby authorized and required each year to reserve and set apart from the first moneys received into the Treasury from taxes for the support of the State Government, and from loans made by the State an amount of money sufficient to pay the semi-annual interest which may become due upon the bonds sold under the provisions of this act, and also to create a sinking fund of two per centum for the redemption of the principal of the said bonds so sold. In accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with section twenty-three, of article twelve, of the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the State, all the provisions of this section shall be irre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealable until the principal and interest of the bonds provided for in this act shall have been fully paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That each year, immediately upon setting aside this sinking fund, as required by section six of this act, it shall be the duty of the Treasurer of the State to give thirty days&#8217; notice by publication in some newspaper, published in the city of New York, having a large circulation, that he will receive sealed proposals for the purchase from the lowest bidder of such an amount of the bonds, provided for in this act, as the sinking fund in the Treasury shall enable him to purchase. The sealed proposals herein provided for shall be opened by the Treasurer in the presence of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor and Comptroller, and the sinking fund in the Treasury shall be applied to the redemption of the bonds offered at the lowest rate. The bonds so purchased shall be burnt at once in the presence of the Governor, Comptroller and Treasurer of the State, who shall to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="67" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>gether sign a certificate, certifying the destruction of said bonds in accordance with the requirements of this section, and setting forth the registered number and value of each of the bonds so destroyed, and said certificate shall be filed in the office of the Comptroller of Public Accounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the sum of five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, to pay the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of engraving and printing the bonds provided for in this act, and the plates used in engraving and printing the said bonds shall be cancelled or destroyed under the direction of the Governor, and a certificate to that effect shall be filed in the office of the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller of Public Accounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Authenticate the Records of the County Court of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston County, Sitting for the Settlement of the Estates of De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased Persons, etc., During the Terms of said Court Holden from and after the first day of July, A. D. 1858, and the thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tieth day of August, 1864.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the minutes which contain and constitute the proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings, orders and decrees of the County Court of Galveston county, sitting for the administration and settlement of the estates of de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased persons, minors and persons non compos mentis, for all of the terms of said court, both regular and called, and during the whole term, commencing on the first day of July, A. D. 1858, and ending on the thirtieth day of August, A. D. 1864, be and the same are hereby fully authenticated and validated, notwithstanding there may appear no signature of the Chief Justice of said county or the presiding judge of said court to said minutes during said term of years from on the first day of July, A. D. 1858, to and on the thirtieth day of August, A. D. 1864, and said minutes are here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by declared to be as valid, both in law and equity, as if said minutes had been signed by said Chief Justice of the county or presiding judge of said court.</p>
<pb n="68" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That said records, or any part thereof, shall be admitted as evidence in any matter or thing, proceeding, order or decree of said court, the same as if said minutes or records had been duly signed by said Chief Justice of the county or presiding judge of said court.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Honorable James P. Love, who was the Chief Justice of Galveston county for and during the said terms of said County Court hereinbefore stated, and who did sit as the presiding judge of said County Court during said terms, be and he is hereby authorized to attach his signature to said minutes or records, and said minutes and records shall be as valid as if signed by him at the proper time.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Concerning Private Corporations.</salute>
</opener>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article I.&#8212;Preliminary Provisions.</head>
<p>Section 1. Corporations are either, first, public; or, second, private.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. A public corporation is one that has for its object the government of a portion of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Private corporations are of three kinds: first, religious; second, corporations for charity or benevolence; and, third, corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rations for profit.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article II.&#8212;Creation of Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 4. Privates corporations may be created by the voluntary association of three or more persons, for the purposes and in the manner mentioned in the following sections of this article.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The purposes for which the corporations mentioned in the last section may be formed, are:</p>
<p>1. The support of public worship.</p>
<p>2. The support of any benevolent, charitable, educational or missionary undertaking.</p>
<p>3. The support of any literary or scientific undertaking, the main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="69" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tenance of a library or the promotion of painting, music or other fine arts.</p>
<p>4. The encouragement of agriculture and horticulture.</p>
<p>5. The maintenance of public parks, and of facilities for skating and other innocent sports.</p>
<p>6. The maintenance of a public or private cemetery.</p>
<p>7. The purchase, location and subdivision of lands, and the sale and conveyance of the same, in lots and subdivisions or otherwise.</p>
<p>8. The construction and maintenance of any species of road, except a railroad, and of bridges in connection therewith.</p>
<p>9. The construction and maintenance of a bridge.</p>
<p>10. The construction and maintenance of a telegraph line.</p>
<p>11. The establishment and maintenance of a ferry.</p>
<p>12. The establishment and maintenance of a line of stages.</p>
<p>13. The building and navigation of steamboats, and carriage of persons and property thereon.</p>
<p>14. The supply of water to the public.</p>
<p>15. The manufacture and supply of gas, or the supply of light or heat to the public by any other means.</p>
<p>16. The transaction of any manufacturing, mining, mechanical or chemical business.</p>
<p>17. The transaction of a printing and publishing business.</p>
<p>18. The establishment and maintenance of a hotel.</p>
<p>19. The erection of buildings and the accumulation and loan, of funds for the purchase of real property.</p>
<p>20. The improvement of the breed of domestic animals by im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portation, sale or otherwise.</p>
<p>21. The transportation of goods, wares and merchandise or any valuable thing.</p>
<p>22. The promotion of immigration.</p>
<p>23. The construction and maintenance of sewers.</p>
<p>24. The construction and maintenance of a street railway.</p>
<p>25. The erection and maintenance of market houses and market places.</p>
<p>26. The construction and maintenance of canals for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of irrigation or manufacturing purposes.</p>
<p>27. For any other purpose intended for mutual profit or benefit not otherwise especially provided for, and not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. A charter must be prepared setting forth&#8212;</p>
<p>1. The name of the corporation.</p>
<p>2. The purpose for which it is formed.</p>
<p>3. The place or places where its business is to be transacted.</p>
<p>4. The term for which it is to exist.</p>
<pb n="70" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>5. The number of its directors or trustees, and the names and residences of those who are appointed for the first year; and</p>
<p>6. The amount of its capital stock, if any, and the number of shares into which it is divided.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The charter of a road company must also state:</p>
<p>1. The kind of road intended to be constructed.</p>
<p>2. The places from and to which the road is intended to be run.</p>
<p>3. The counties through which it is intended to be run.</p>
<p>4. The estimated length of the road.</p>
<p>5. The charter of a bridge or ferry company shall also state the stream intended to be crossed by the bridge or ferry.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The charter of an intended corporation must be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by three or more persons, two of whom, at least, must be citizens of this State, and must be acknowledged by them before an officer, duly authorized to take acknowledgments of deeds.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Such charter shall thereupon be filed in the office of the Secretary of State, who shall record the same, at length, in a book to be kept for that purpose, and retain the original on file in his office. A copy of the charter, or of the record thereof, duly cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified by the Secretary of State, under the great seal of the State, shall be evidence of the creation of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The existence of the corporation shall date from the time of filing the charter, and the certificate of the Secretary of State shall be evidence of the time of such filing.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article III.&#8212;Powers and Duties of Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 11. Every corporation, as such, has power:</p>
<p>1. To have succession by its corporate name for the period limited in its charter, and when no period is limited, for twenty years.</p>
<p>2. To maintain and defend judicial proceedings.</p>
<p>3. To make and use a common seal.</p>
<p>4. To hold, purchase, sell, mortgage, or otherwise convey such real and personal estate as the purposes of the corporation shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire, and also to take, hold and convey such other property, real personal or mixed, as shall be requisite for such corporation to acquire in order to obtain or secure the payment of any indebted<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness or liability due to or belonging to the corporation.</p>
<p>5. To appoint and remove such subordinate officers and agents as the business of the corporation shall require, and to allow them a suitable compensation.</p>
<p>6. To make by-laws not inconsistent with existing laws for the<pb n="71" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>management of its property, the regulation of its affairs, and for the transfer of its stock.</p>
<p>7. To enter into any obligation or contract essential to the transaction of its ordinary affairs.</p>
<p>8. To increase or diminish, by a vote of its stockholders, cast as its by-laws may direct, the number of its directors or trustees, to be not less than three nor more than thirteen.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Any corporation may increase its capital stock to any amount not exceeding double the amount of their authorized cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ital, by a vote of the stockholders, in conformity with the by-laws thereof; and if a majority of the stockholders shall vote for the increase of stock, the same may be increased by the board of di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, trustees or other business managers of such corporation; and upon such increase of stock being made in accordance with the by-laws, the date and amount of such increase shall be certified to the Secretary of State by the directors or trustees, and from the time such certificate is filed the increase of stock shall become a part of the capital thereof. Such certificate shall be filed and recorded in the same manner as the charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Corporations shall have power to borrow money on the credit of the corporation, not exceeding its authorized capital stock, and may execute bonds or promissory notes therefor, and may pledge the property and income of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Whenever the full amount of the capital stock of a corporation having a capital stock shall not have been already sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed in good faith, the directors or trustees named in the charter, or a majority of them, may, within three months after the filing of the charter, cause books to be opened for receiving subscription to the capital stock of the corporation, at such time or times, and at such place or places, as they may determine, after having given at least thirty days&#8217; notice in a newspaper published or generally cir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culated in one or more counties where books of subscription are to be opened, of the time and place of opening books, which books may be kept open till the whole amount of capital stock is sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. A majority of the directors or trustees shall constitute a quorum, and be competent to fill vacancies in the board, and to transact all business of the corporation. An annual election shall he held for directors or trustees, at such time and place as the by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws of the corporation may require.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. The directors or trustees shall choose one of their num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber president, and shall appoint a secretary and treasurer, and such other officers as they may deem necessary for the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. The directors or trustees may adopt by-laws for the<pb n="72" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>government of the corporation; but such by-laws may be altered, changed or amended by a majority vote of the stockholders at any election or special meeting ordered for that purpose by the direct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors or trustees, on a written application of a majority of the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders or members.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. All corporations heretofore created and now in exist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence under any law of this State, are hereby authorized to increase the number of directors or trustees of any such corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. In case it should happen that an election for directors or trustees should not be held on the day appointed by the by-laws of any corporation formed under the provisions of this act, such corporation shall not, for that reason, be deemed to be dissolved, but it shall be lawful on any other day to hold a meeting and elect its directors or trustees in such manner as shall be prescribed by the by-laws thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. The secular affairs of a religious corporation shall be under the control of a board of trustees, to be elected by the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of such corporation, and the title to all property of any such corporation shall vest in such trustees.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. The directors or trustees shall have the general man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agement of the affairs of the corporation, and may dispose of the residue of the capital stock at any time remaining unsubscribed, in such manner as the by-laws may prescribe. They shall cause a record to be kept of all stock subscribed and transferred, and of all business transactions, and their books and records shall, at all reasonable times, be open to the inspection of any and every stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holder. They shall, also, when required by one-third of the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders thereof, present reports in writing of the situation and amount of business of the corporation, and declare and make such dividends of the profits from the business of the corporation as they shall deem expedient, or as the by-laws may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. Any corporation heretofore organized and now in ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istence under any general or special law of the Republic or the State of Texas, may, by a vote of its board of directors, accept any or all the provisions of this act, and have and exercise all the rights, power and priviliges conferred by this act, by filing a copy of their acceptance with the Secretary of State; whereupon, that portion of their charter inconsistent with this act, or the portion accepted, shall cease to be applicable to such corporation; and they shall have the exclusive right to carry out the objects of said corporation as de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed in their act of incorporation or certificate filed with the Secretary of State, if acting under a general law within the limits and boundaries described in said act of incorporation, or certificate, as the ease may be, without any limitation as to time, and shall pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="73" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sess all the privileges and. franchises conferred by their act of incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration or certificate filed with the Secretary of State, not aban<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />doned in the copy of acceptance of any or all the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. No corporation created under the provisions of this act shall employ its stock, means, assets, or other property, directly or indirectly, for any other purpose whatever, than to accomplish the legitimate objects of the creation.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. The stock of any corporation created under this act shall be deemed personal estate; and shall be transferable only on the books of the corporation in such manner as the by-laws may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. The board of directors or trustees of any corporation may require the subscribers to the capital stock of the corporation to pay the amount by them respectively subscribed, in such manner and in such instalments as may be required by the by-laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. If any stockholder shall neglect to pay any instal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, as required by the board of trustees, the directors or trustees may declare his stock and all previous payments forfeited to the use of the company; but no stock shall be forfeited until the di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors or trustees have caused a notice in writing to be served on him personally, or by depositing the same in the postoffice, proper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly directed to him at the postoffice nearest his usual place of resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence, stating that he is required to make such payment at the time and place specified in said notice, and that if he fails to make the same, his stock and all previous payments thereon, will be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feited for the use of the company; which notice may be served, as aforesaid, at least thirty days previous to the day on which such payment is required to be made.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. All bodies corporate may sue for, recover and receive from their respective members, all arrears or other debts, dues or other demands, which now are, or hereafter may be owing to them, in like mode, manner and form, as they might sue for, recover and receive the same from any person who might be one of their body.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. If the directors of any corporation shall knowingly de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clare and pay any dividend, when the corporation is insolvent, or any dividend the payment of which would render it insolvent, they shall be jointly and severally liable for all the debts of the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion then existing, and for all that shall be thereafter contracted, as long as they shall respectively continue in office. The amount for which they shall all be so liable shall not exceed the amount of such dividend; and if any of the directors shall be absent at the time of making the dividend, or shall object thereto at the time such divi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dend is declared, and shall file their objection in writing with the<pb n="74" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>secretary or other officer of the corporation having charge of the books, they shall be exempted from the said liability.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article IV.&#8212;Miscellaneous Provisions.</head>
<p>Sec. 29. If any execution shall have been issued against the property or effects of a corporation except a railway or a religious or charitable corporation, and there cannot be found any property whereon to levy such execution, then execution may be issued against any of the stockholders to an extent equal the amount to the amount of stock by him or her owned, together with any amount unpaid thereon; but no execution shall issue against any stockholder, except upon an order of the court in which the action, suit, or other proceeding, shall have been brought or instituted, made upon motion in open court, after reasonable notice in writing to the person or persons sought to be charged; and upon such mo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, such court may order execution to issue accordingly; or the plaintiff in the execution may proceed by action to charge the stockholders with the amount of his judgment.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. The clerk or other officer having charge of the books of any corporation, on demand of the plaintiff in any execution against the corporation, his agent or attorney, shall furnish such plaintiff, his agent or attorney with the names and places of resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence of the stockholders (so far as known,) and the amount of stock held by each, as shown by the books of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. Whenever any company heretofore incorporated for the purpose of erecting any public improvement in this State, whose charter is limited as to the time for completion of said im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provement, and when any such company has been legally organized and has actually commenced and has in progress toward completion such public improvement, it shall be lawful for any such company to have further time allowed for the final completion of said work as is hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. Upon petition being filed by the directors of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration in the district court of any county in which the principal office of such corporation is located, and upon giving thirty days&#8217; notice by publication in newspaper of general circulation in said county, of the object and prayer of such petition, said court shall, at any regular term, after publication of said notice, on good cause shown, decree the extension of the time for the completion of said improvement, to such period as shall appear to such court just and reasonable.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. Each corporation or joint stock company, of every de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription, whether organized and acting under a special charter or<pb n="75" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>general law of the State, shall keep its principal office within this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. No misnomer of any corporation shall defeat or vitiate any gift, grant, conveyance, devise or bequest to the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. Any corporation may convey lands by deed, sealed with the common seal of the corporation, and signed by the presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent or the presiding member or trustee of said corporation; and such deed, when acknowledged by such officer to be the act of the corporation, or proved in the manner prescribed for other convey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances of lands, may be recorded in like manner and with the same effect as other deeds.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. The records of any company incorporated under the provisions of any statute of this State, or copies thereof duly authenticated by the signature of the president and secretary of such company, under the corporate seal thereof, shall be competent evidence in any action or proceeding to which such corporation may be a party.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article V.&#8212;Dissolution of Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 37. A corporation is dissolved: first, by the expiration, of the time limited in its charter; second, by a judgment of dissolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion rendered by a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. Every corporation created under this act or any gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral law of this State, shall commence active operations within three years after filing its charter with the Secretary of State, and in default thereof said corporation shall be dissolved and its charter become void.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. Upon the dissolution of any corporation already created by or under the laws of this State, unless a receiver is ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed by some court of competent authority, the president and directors or managers of the affairs of the corporation at the time of its dissolution, by whatever name they may be known in law, shall be trustees of the creditors and stockholders of such corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, with full power to settle the affairs, collect the outstanding debts, and divide the moneys and other property among the stock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />holders, after paying the debts due and owing by such corporation at the time of its dissolution as far as such money and property will enable them; and for this purpose they may maintain or defend any -judicial proceeding.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. The trustees mentioned in the last section shall be severally responsible to the creditors and stockholders of such cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration to the extent of its property and effects that shall have come into their hands.</p>
<pb n="76" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 41. If any corporation created under this or any general statute of this State, except railway, or charitable or religious cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porations, be dissolved, leaving debts unpaid, suits may be brought against any person or persons who were stockholders at the time of such dissolution, without joining the corporation in such suit, and if judgment be rendered and execution satisfied, the defendant or defendants may sue all who were stockholders at the time of disso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lution for the recovery of the portion of such debt for which they were liable, and the execution upon the judgment shall direct the collection to be made from property of each stockholder respect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ively, and if any number of stockholders (defendants in the case) shall not have property enough to satisfy his or their portion of the execution, then the amount of deficiency shall be divided equally among all the remaining stockholders, and collections made accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ingly, deducting from the amount a sum in proportion to the amount of stock owned by the plaintiff at the time the company dissolved.</p>
<p>Sec. 42. If any stockholder pay more than his due proportion of any debt of the corporation, he may compel contribution from the other stockholders by action.</p>
<p>Sec. 43. No stockholder shall be liable to pay debts of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration beyond the amount due on his stock and an additional amount equal to the stock owned by him.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article VI.&#8212;Macadam and Plank Road Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 44. It shall be lawful for any corporation created for the purpose of constructing a macadam or plank road, by its agents and servants to enter upon any lands to make surveys, estimates and locations.</p>
<p>Sec. 45. If any such corporation shall require for the construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or repairs of its road, or any bridge thereof, any stone, timber or other material from land adjoining to or near said road, and can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />not contract for the same with the owner thereof, such corporation may proceed to have the value of the same assessed, and the same proceedings shall be had therefor as is provided by law to be taken by railway corporations in like cases; and all macadam or plank road corporations shall have the right also to condemn, in like man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, and occupy any quantity of land, not exceeding one acre at any one place, for the purpose of erecting toll houses thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 46. If any road or any part thereof, after it shall have been completed, shall be suffered to be out of repair so as to be impassa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble for the space of two months unless when the same is being re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paired, the company owning such road shall be liable to forfeit its corporate powers and privileges, and such forfeiture may be enforced<pb n="77" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="75" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by action, as provided in the Code of Civil Procedure; and if such company shall suffer the road to be out of repair to the injury, hin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />drance or delay of travelers for an unreasonable time, they shall have no right to collect tolls thereon until the same is again re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paired.</p>
<p>Sec. 47. All macadam or plank roads shall be opened not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding sixty feet wide, thirty feet of which shall be cleared of brush and logs, and at least sixteen feet shall be made of artificial road composed of stone or gravel, or wood, or other convenient material, in such manner as to secure a firm and substantial road. No company or association of individuals which have been or may hereafter be incorporated for the purpose of making such road, shall erect or keep any toll gate or receive any toll within the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate limits of any incorporated city, town or village, or within one hundred and sixty rods of such limits.</p>
<p>Sec. 48. As soon as such road shall have been completed, or any part thereof, not less than five miles together in any part of the road, unless the same is less than five miles long, and so from time to time, as often as five miles in addition shall be completed adjoin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing any five miles previously constructed, the county court of the county in which such finished road lies, or, in case the road lies in two or more counties, the county courts of either of said counties shall, on application of the agent of the company, appoint three judicious householders, who shall, on oath, examine the same, and report their opinion to the court in writing; and if such report shall state that the road, or such part thereof, to be completed agreeably to the provisions of this act, the court shall by license, in writing, authorize the company to erect gates at suitable dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tances and demand and receive of persons traveling such road the toll that may be fixed by the county court.</p>
<p>Sec. 49. Any person or persons going to or from public worship on the Sabbath, common schools and other institutions of learning, funerals, militia muster, the troops of the United States and of this State, may pass any such road free from toll.</p>
<p>Sec. 50. All macadam or plank road companies shall put up a post or stone at the end of each mile, with the number from begin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning of said road, fairly cut or printed thereon; and also in a con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spicuous place near each gate shall be placed a board with the rates of toll painted thereon, and no toll shall be demanded unless such rates are kept up.</p>
<p>Sec. 51. If any macadam or plank road company shall fail to keep their road in repair for five days successively, any person may file a complaint in writing, before any justice of the peace of the county, setting forth the nature of the defect complained of, desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nating the place in the road where it exists; and it shall be the duty<pb n="78" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="76" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of the justice to appoint two disinterested persons as inspectors, to meet at the place complained of within five days, and of the time and place of meeting reasonable notice shall be given to the gate keeper nearest to the place of meeting, and the inspectors shall then examine into the truth of the matter complained of; and if they shall find the complaint to be true, they shall send a certified copy of the complaint and of the finding thereon to the keeper of each of the gates between which such defective place shall be, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after no toll shall be received at such gates for the intermediate dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tance, until the part of the road complained of shall be fully re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paired; and the inspectors and justice of the peace shall be entitled to two dollars and a half per day for their services, and shall be paid by the company if the complaint be sustained, and if it shall fail, then by the complainant.</p>
<p>Sec. 52. If any person or persons using any part of said road shall, with intent to defraud such company, or shall falsely repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent himself or herself to any toll gatherer as entitled to exemption from paying toll, or shall make any untrue statement as to the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tance he or they shall have traveled or intend to travel on the road, or shall practice any fraudulent means, and thereby lessen or avoid the payment of tolls, each and every person concerned in any such fraudulent practices shall, for every such offense, forfeit and pay to such company the sum of five dollars, to be recovered by such com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany in an action of debt before any justice of the peace of the county where the offender may be found.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article VII.&#8212;Telegraph Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 53 Corporations created for the purpose of constructing and maintaining magnetic telegraph lines are authorized to set their poles, piers, abutments, wires and other fixtures, along, upon and across any of the public roads, streets and waters of this State, in such manner as not to incommode the public in the use of such roads, streets and waters.</p>
<p>Sec. 54. Such companies are also authorized to enter upon any lands, whether owned by private persons in fee or in any less estate, or by any corporation whether acquired by purchase or by virtue of any provision in the charter of such corporation, for the purpose of making preliminary surveys and examinations with a view to the erection of any telegraph lines, and from time to time to appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate so much of said lands as may be necessary to erect such poles, piers, abutments, wires and other necessary fixtures for a magnetic telegraph, and to make such changes of location of any part of said lines as may from time to time be deemed necessary, and shall have<pb n="79" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="77" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>a right to access to construct said line, and when erected, from time to time as may be required to repair the same, and may proceed to obtain the right of way, and to condemn lands for the use of the corporation, in the manner provided by law in case of railway corporations.</p>
<p>Sec. 55. No corporation shall have power to contract with any owner of land for the right to erect and maintain a telegraph line, over his lands to the exclusion of the lines of other companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 56. Any corporation, created as herein provided, may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract, own, use and maintain any line or lines of telegraph, whether wholly within, or wholly or partly beyond, the limits of this State, and shall have power to lease or attach to the line or lines of such corporation other telegraph lines, by lease or purchase, and may join with any other corporation or association in constructing, leas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, owning, using or maintaining their line or lines upon such terms as may be agreed upon between the directors or managers of the respective corporations, and may own and hold any interest in such line or lines, or may become lessees thereof on such terms as the respective corporations may agree.</p>
<p>Sec. 57. The council of any city, or trustee of any incorpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted town or village through which the line of any telegraph corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration is to pass, may, by ordinance or otherwise, specify where the posts, piers or abutments shall be located, the kind of posts that shall be used, the height at which the wires shall be run, and such company shall be governed by the regulations thus prescribed; and after erection of said telegraph lines, the council of any city, or the trustees of any incorporated town or village, shall have power to di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect any alteration in the erection or location of said posts, piers or abutments, and also in the height at which the wires shall run, having first given such company or its agents opportunity to be heard in regard to such alteration.</p>
<p>Sec. 58. Any person who shall wilfully and intentionally in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jure, molest or destroy any of the lines, post, piers, abutments or other material or property pertaining to any line of telegraph erect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed in this State, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall upon conviction, in the court having criminal jurisdiction in the proper county be punished by fine, not exceeding five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment in the county jail, not exceeding one year, or by both; such fine and imprisonment at the discretion of the court having cognizance thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 59. Any telegraph company now organized, or which may hereafter be organized under the laws of this States, may, at any regular meeting of the stockholders thereof, by vote of persons holding a majority of shares of the stock of such company, unite or<pb n="80" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="78" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>consolidate with any other company or companies now organized, or which may hereafter be organized under the laws of the United States, or of any State or territory, by the consent of the company with which it may consolidate or unite; and such company so formed may hold, use and enjoy all the rights and privileges con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred by the laws of Texas on companies separately organized un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the provisions of this act, and be subject to the same liabilities.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article VIII.&#8212;Appropriation of lands for the use of railway and other corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 60. Lands may be appropriated for the use of macadam, plank road and telegraph corporations in the same manner as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in the general laws of this State for railway corporations, as far as applicable.</p>
<p>Sec. 61. Every canal corporation for the purpose of irrigation shall, in addition to the powers heretofore conferred, have power:</p>
<p>1. To cause such examination and survey for its proposed canal to be made as may be necessary to the selection of the most advan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tageous route, and for such purpose by its officers, agents or serv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ants to enter upon the lands or waters of any person.</p>
<p>2. To take and hold such voluntary grant of real and other property as shall be made to it to aid in the construction and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of its canal, ditches and sluices.</p>
<p>3. To construct its canal across, along or upon any stream of water.</p>
<p>4. To furnish water for irrigation at such rates as such organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation or corporation may by its by-laws and regulations prescribe.</p>
<p>5. To borrow such sums of money as may be necessary for com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pleting and finishing or operating their canal, and to issue and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of their bonds for any amount so borrowed, and to mortgage their corporate property and franchises to secure the payment of any debt contracted by the operation for the purposes aforesaid; provided, that damages for any property appropriated by such cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration shall be assessed and paid for as is provided for in case of railroads.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article IX.&#8212;Gas and Water Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 62. Any gas or water corporation shall have full power to manufacture and sell and to furnish such quantities of gas or water as may be required by the city, town or village where located, for public or private buildings or for other purposes, and such cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration shall have power to lay pipes, mains and conductors for<pb n="81" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="79" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>conducting gas or water through the streets, lanes, alleys and squares in such city, town or village, with the consent of the mu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nicipal authorities thereof, and under such regulations as they may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 63. The municipal authorities of any city, town or village in which any gas light or water corporation shall exist, are hereby authorized to contract with any such corporation for the lighting or supplying with water the streets, lots, lanes, squares and public places in any such city, town or village.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article X.&#8212;Colleges, Academies, Etc.</head>
<p>Sec. 64. The president, professors or principals shall constitute the faculty in academy, college or university, and shall have power to enforce the rules and regulations enacted by the directors or trustees for the government and discipline of the students, and to suspend and expel offenders, as may be deemed necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 65. The directors or trustees named in the charter, as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by this act, of any college, academy, university or other institution to promote education, and their successors may make all necessary by-laws, elect and employ officers, provide for filling vacancies, appoint and remove professors, teachers, agents, etc., and fix their compensation, confer degrees, and do and perform any and all necessary acts to carry into effect the objects of the corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 66. Such corporations may procure, to be used as a part of the course of education, shops, tools and machinery, land for agri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cultural purposes, and necessary buildings for carrying on their mechanical and agricultural operations.</p>
<p>Sec. 67. Any such corporation may convert its property, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept when held upon some special trust, into stock or scholarships, and file a certificate of their action, as required in the case of an in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />crease of capital stock of a corporation. Such conversion can only take place by the consent of a majority of the stockholders.</p>
<p>Sec. 68. The directors of any such corporation, whose property is held not as stock, but upon trust or by devise, donation, gift or subscription, shall not contract debts beyond the means of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration. If they do contract debts to a larger amount, they shall be held individually liable for the same, after the means of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration are exhausted.</p>
<p>Sec. 69. Any such corporation may, by a vote of three-fourths of the directors, or if the same is owned in shares of stock, then by a vote of three-fourths of the stockholders, change the location and name of the institution, and transfer the effects thereof to where<pb n="82" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="80" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>removed, or may apply the property thereof to other purposes of education than those named in the original charter filed with the Secretary of State.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article XI.&#8212;Religions, Charitable and other Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 70. Any religions society, military or fire company, liter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, social, charitable or benevolent association, other than colleges, universities, academies or seminaries, or any grand or subordinate lodge or other order of Free and Accepted Mason, or of the In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dependent order of Odd Fellows may, by the consent of a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of its members, become bodies corporate under this act, by filing the charter required by this act, electing directors or trus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tees, and performing the things as directed in the case of other corporations; and when so organized, shall have all the powers and privileges, and be subject to all the restrictions in this act contained for the objects named in the charter, and shall have the same power to make by-laws for the regulation of their affairs as other corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions. Such directors or trustees shall not usurp or exercise the functions of the officers in charge of the spiritual affairs of any society.</p>
<p>Sec. 71. No religious, literary, social, scientific, industrial, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nevolent, or other society, association, company, corporation or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution that does not have a capital stock, will be required, in its charter, to make any statement of the amount of capital stock or amount of each share; but such charter, if it contains the other statements therein required, and also an estimate of the value of the goods, chattels, lands, rights and credits owned by the corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration will be sufficient.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article XII.&#8212;Cemetery Corporations.</head>
<p>Sec. 72. Cemetery corporations shall have power to divide the land of the cemetery into lots and sub-divisions for the purposes of the cemetery, and to tax the property for the purpose of its general improvement.</p>
<p>Sec. 73. Such corporation shall have power to convey, by deed or otherwise, any lot or lots of the cemetery for purposes of sepul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture. When such lots shall have been surveyed and platted, the survey and plat shall be recorded in the office of the district clerk of the county wherein the same are situated, and shall not be after<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wards changed or altered. No lots shall be sold or disposed of until such plat shall have been recorded. All the ground held by such corporation for burial purposes, while so held, shall be exempt<pb n="83" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="81" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>from public taxation. Every lot sold and conveyed in such ceme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tery shall be held by the proprietor for purposes of sepulture only, and shall not be subject to attachment or execution.</p>
<p>Sec. 74. All owners of lots purchased of any such corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall become members thereof and be entitled to vote in the election of its officers and upon any other matters to the same ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent as stockholders in other corporations.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article XIII.&#8212;Savings Banks.</head>
<p>Sec. 75. Any five or more persons in any county in this State may organize themselves into a savings association, and shall be per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted to carry on the business of receiving money on deposit, and to allow interest thereon, giving to the persons depositing credit therefor; and of buying and selling exchange, gold, silver, coin, bullion, uncurrent money, bonds of the United States, of the State of Texas, and of the city, county and school district in which any association shall organize; of loaning money on real estate and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal security at such rate of interest as may be agreed upon; and of discounting negotiable notes and notes not negotiable; and on all loans made may keep and receive the interest in advance.</p>
<p>Sec. 76. The capital stock of any such association shall be not less than fifty thousand nor more than five hundred thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, to be divided into shares of not less than one hundred dollars each, of which ten per centum upon each share shall be paid at the time the same shall be subscribed, the remainder of the stock so subscribed shall be paid upon such calls and upon such terms as the directors may from time to time prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 77. The affairs and business of any such association shall be managed and controlled by a board of directors not less than five nor more than nine in number, who shall designate a president, a cashier and a secretary, and such other officers as the association may require, who shall hold their office for one year, until their successors are elected and duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 78. Before any such corporation shall commence its busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, a majority of the shares thereof shall have been subscribed for and the entrance fees thereon paid in, and the president and secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary thereof, under their hands and seals, shall have made a certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate which shall specify&#8212;first, the corporate name of such corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; second, the name of the city or town in which such incorpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion is to be located; third, the amount of its capital stock and the number of shares into which the same shall be divided; fourth, the names and places of residence of the stockholders and the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of shares held by each; fifth, the time when such corporation<pb n="84" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="82" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>was organized; which certificate shall be acknowledged before a notary public and recorded in the registry of deeds for the county in which such corporation is to be located, and a copy thereof and of the by-laws of the said association shall be filed in the office of the Secretary of State, and copies of such certificates, duly at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tested by the clerk of the district court or Secretary of State, shall be admitted as sufficient evidence in all the courts of law and on all occasions whatever; provided however, that no corporation established under the provisions of this charter shall take the name of any corporation or association heretofore organized or in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated in this State for similar purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 79. Every such corporation shall semi-annually, in the months of July and January, publish in one or more newspapers in the county where such corporation shall have its place of business, a statement verified by the oath of its president or secretary, setting forth its actual financial condition, and the amount of its property and liabilities, under a penalty of five hundred dollars to the State, to be recovered by indictment against the president, cashier or di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectors, and shall also deposit a copy of said statement, verified as aforesaid, in the office of the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 80. Dividends of the net profits of such association shall be declared on the first days of July and January of each year, unless some different time is fixed by the by-laws of such corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 81. All other acts and parts of acts inconsistent with this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 82. This act to take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Amendatory to An Act Entitled An Act to Provide for the Organization of the State Lunatic Asylum, and for the Care and Maintenance of the Insane, Approved February 5, 1858.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article four of said act shall be so amended as to read as follows: The managers of the asylum shall elect, subject to the approval of the Governor, a treasurer for the asylum, who shall,<pb n="85" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="83" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>either himself or by agencies, collect all its dues and pay out its revenues only in conformity with the laws of the State and the by<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />laws of the institution. He shall give a bond, made payable to the State, in the sum of ten thousand dollars, with two or more suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient sureties, to be approved by the board of managers, and shall perform his services as such treasurer, with compensation. He shall report to the Governor on the first day of October of each year.</p>
<p>That article seventeen be so amended as to read as follows: The amount to be paid for the board of patients admitted into the hos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pital shall be at the rate of four dollars per week for each person supported by the county, etc., instead of: The amount to be paid for the board of patients admitted into the hospital shall be at the rate of two dollars per week, etc.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="86" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="84" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
