<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="87" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="85" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution Authorizing the Appointment of Commissioners to Run, Mark Out and Fully Define the County Lines of San Jacinto County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of the State of Texas be and is hereby empowered to appoint commissioners to ran, mark out and fully define the county lines and boundaries of the county of San Jacinto, and that the lines and boundaries so marked and defined shall be and are hereby declared to be the lines and boundaries of the county of San Jacinto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this joint resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>October 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution Instructing and Requesting Our Congressional Delegation to Urge upon Congress the Reimbursement to Cot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Raisers of the Cotton Tax Imposed upon the Products of the Soil by Act of Congress in 1864, 1866 and 1867.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Congress of the United States with the view (as was alleged) to increase the internal revenue of the general govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, enacted certain laws, to-wit: one approved on the thirtieth day of June, 1864, which levied a duty of two cents per pound on all cotton, the growth of the United States; another approved<pb n="88" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="86" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw> thirteenth July, 1866, fixing in lieu of the foregoing a tax on cotton of three cents per pound; another approved on the second day of March, 1867, reducing the said tax from the first of September, 1867, to two and a half cents per pound; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, at different times, by regulations of the Treasury de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment, and at other times by military orders, special taxes were levied on cotton, sometimes at specific rates per pound and at other times payable in kind; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the collection of the aforesaid taxes and duties were rigidly enforced to the great detriment of the agricultural interests of the cotton growing portion of the United States where said cot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton was (with the exception of a very few bales grown, and often terminating in the bankruptcy of the producer; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the Constitution of the United States guarantees to the several States equal distribution of taxation, and in which an export tax is prohibited, and as a tax upon the production of the soil was without constitutional warrant, especially as its application was limited to but one article of production, and therefore not uniform; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the constitutional right of Congress to enact such laws was always exceeding doubtful and now ascertained to be so by the late decision of the Supreme Court of the United States, in the case of Farrington vs. Saunders, wherein the court stood equally divided four to four and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the people of Texas, colored as well as white, are in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terested in the return of this money, and jointly look with solici<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tude to the action of those who control the destinies of our country, acting in their official capacity,</p>
<p>Be it therefore resolved by the Senate and House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives of the State of Texas, That, in view of the facts as herein set forth, Congress is earnestly requested to restore and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fund to the parties respectively interested all moneys so, as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, collected of the people of Texas, under and by virtue of the aforesaid acts and supplemental acts and orders relative to said taxation of cotton; and be it further</p>
<p>Resolved, That the Senators in Congress be instructed and our congressional Representatives requested to do all in their power to aid in having said money restored by the government of the United States to the parties from whom it was collected.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 1, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="89" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="87" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the Relief of James H. Skinner, Sheriff of Henderson County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, On the eleventh day of September, 1871, at the city of Austin, one hundred and sixty dollars in United States cur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rency, revenue of the State of Texas, collected by James H. Skin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner, sheriff of Henderson county, on the tax assessment of the year 1871, was stolen from the Hon. W. B. Stirman, by whom it was being sent to the Treasury, without fault of said sheriff or his said agent; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate and House of representatives of the State of Texas, That James H. Skinner, sheriff of Henderson county be, and he is hereby relieved from any and all liability on account of the loss of said one hundred and sixty dollars, and that the Comptroller of Public Accounts is hereby authorized and required to credit said sheriff by the aforesaid amount in the set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlement of his accounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this resolution take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>November 13, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution to Defray the Expenses of Printing the Reports of all Officers Who Are Required to Report to the Governor or the Legislature by Section Five of An Act Regulating Public Printing, Approved August 13, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of four thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be required, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to defray the expenses of printing reports delivered to the present Legislature by the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this joint resolution take effect from and alter its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="90" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="88" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution Prescribing the Duties of the Inspector of the State Penitentiary.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Inspector of the Penitentiary be and be is hereby authorized to receive and disburse all moneys belonging to the State, apper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining to the penitentiary, and generally to do and perform all things which the Financial Agent of the State was formerly authorized or required to do. And for the faithful performance of this duty the Governor shall require of such inspector a bond payable to the State of Texas, in such an amount as may be fixed by the Governor, which bond shall be approved by the Governor.</p>
<p>This joint resolution shall take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>December 2, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ERRATA.</head>
<p>Chapter XXVI, section 1, article 568, clause 9, line 1&#8212;&#8220;where&#8221; lieu of &#8220;when.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chapter XXXII, section 4, line 9&#8212;&#8220;claims&#8221; in lieu of &#8220;claim.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chapter XXXIV, section 1, line 18&#8212;&#8220;owning&#8221; in lieu of &#8220;owing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chapter XLIII, section 7, line 3&#8212;strike out &#8220;now&#8221; after &#8220;money.&#8221; Also, section 8, line 2&#8212;insert &#8220;the&#8221; after &#8220;in command of.&#8221; Also, section 8, line 4&#8212;&#8220;permanently&#8221; in lieu of &#8220;prema<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turely.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chapter XLVII, section 2, line 3&#8212;&#8220;fifteen&#8221; in lieu of &#8220;hfteen.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chapter LVIII, title&#8212;&#8220;supplemental in lieu of &#8220;suaplemental."</p>
<p>LXIV, section 1, line 10&#8212;strike out a&#8221; after &#8220;by."</p>
<p>Chapter LXXVI, section 2, line 11&#8212;&#8220;by&#8221; in lieu of &#8220;be."</p>
</div2>
<pb n="91" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="89" />
<div2 type="article">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concurrent Resolution in Relation to the Appointment of Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitteees to Attend the Centennial Celebration to be held at Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in the Year 1876.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Senate of the State of Texas, the House of Representatives concurring, Whereas, the Governor of the State of Pennsylvania has forwarded through the Governor of Texas to the Legislature of Texas, a joint resolution of the several assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />blies of Pennsylvania, approved March 8, 1871, to-wit: that the Governor and three persons appointed by him, William A. Wallace and James H. Webb, speakers of the Senate and House, with three members of each branch of the Legislature, to be appointed by the Speakers of the Senate and House respectively, shall be a Commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee of Pennsylvania to co-operate with committees from other States and local committees, upon the subject of the Centennial Celebration at Philadelphia, in the year one thousand eight hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and seventy-six, said committee to stand until that time, and to report at each intervening Legislature, and make such sug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gestions and recommendations from time to time to the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture as they may think proper and expedient in reference to such Centennial Celebration.</p>
<p>Whereas, The Governor of Pennsylvania, in addition to the above resolution of the several assemblies of this State, also communicates the fact of the object of said appointment as follows: One of the most prominent objects of this resolution is to perfect the necessary preliminary organization at the earliest practicable date, and to gather all necessary information and material to facilitate the operations of the United States Board of Commissioners to be appointed by the President of the United States, upon the recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mendations of the Governors of the different States and Territories, in accordance with an act of Congress &#8220;to provide for celebrating the one hundredth anniversary of American independence by hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing an international exhibition of arts, manufactures, and products<pb n="92" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /> <pb ed="unknown" n="90" /><fw type="header" place="top">Concurrent Resolution.</fw>of the soil and mines, in the city of Philadelphia and the State of Pennsylvania, in the year eighteen hundred and seventy-six;&#8221; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, In furtherance of this grand national object of a cen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tennial anniversary celebration and international exhibition, the Governor of Pennsylvania urges the Legislature of Texas to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point a special committee to co-operate with the committee of Pennsylvania, in conformity with the provisions of the joint resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of that State; therefore, be it hereby</p>
<p>Resolved, That the Governor of the State, with three persons to be appointed by him, the President of the Senate, with three Sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors to be appointed by him, and the Speaker of the House, with three members of the House to be appointed by him, shall be a committee to co-operate with the committee of Pennsylvania in furtherance of the centennial celebration of 1876, with like power and authority as conferred upon special committee of Pennsyl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vania, in conformity with the joint resolution of its General Assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bly, passed March 8, 1871.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>November 29, 1871</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, J. E. OLDRIGHT, Acting Secretary of State for the State of Texas, certify that the acts and resolutions contained in this vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ume are true copies, taken from the originals in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>And I further certify that the adjourned session of the Twelfth Legislature of said State commenced at the city of Austin on Tues<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day, the twelfth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and seventy-one, and adjourned sine die on Saturday, the second day of December, in the year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and seventy-one.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name and have caused the seal of the Department of State to be affixed at the city of Austin, this ninth day of January, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and seventy-two.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. E. OLDRIGHT, <lb/>Acting Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>